欢迎收看斯坦福大学公开课
Stanford University.
本字幕由志愿者义务贡献
>> All right, well,welcome to Stanford CS193P,
欢迎参加斯坦福大学 2015 年
winter of 2015.
冬季学期的 CS193P 课程
This is lecture number two.
这是我们的第二讲
I apologize upfront for my terrible voice, we are going
由于我糟糕的嗓音，预先向大家致歉
to try to get through this as best we can today.
我们要尽可能去克服这个困难
Our topics are two fold.
我们的话题有两个方面
We're going to continue the calculator
我们将继续在上一讲中已经开始的计算器 Demo，
demo that we started, in last lecture and then we're gonna
然后我们将会有
have some slides about this model view controller,
一些关于 model view controller，
object-oriented design pattern that we're gonna use in
和面向对象设计模式的课件
everything we do.
这些设计模式我们将要广泛的使用
When we build applications in this class.
当我们在这节课中开发应用时
All right?
有问题么？
So let's get started with that demo.
没问题就让我开始演示 Demo
Again, here's a slide with the summary of kind of
这里是一张总结
the important things we're gonna talk about.
接下去我们即将要讲的重点的幻灯片
You don't need to read those in advance here,
你们并不需要提前去阅读这些
it's more for reference.
它更多地是为了提供参考的
My slides in general, I post them,
我做的课件一般来讲，
it's mostly intended to almost be note taking for you.
主要是为了方便你们记笔记用
To be able go back and try and
为了你们在复习的时候能够
figure out, whoa, when did he talked about that day?
回忆出，我什么时候讲过这些？
Oh yeah.
What's important, et cetera.
什么是重要的，等等
So my slides do tend to be a little bit dense.
所以，我的幻灯片也往往是有点多
I tend to put a little more on them, than,
我更倾向于在上面多放一些内容，
than just bullet items.
而不是一项一项往上列
But that's because I want you to be able to look back and
但是，那是因为我希望你们能够回过头来看的时候
kind of get just a little bit more depth to
对于我所说的
remind yourself what I talked about.
你们会有更深入的理解
Okay?
All right, so
好了，
this demo, if you'll remember last time, where we left off,
关于这个 Demo，如果你们还记得上次我们快结束时，
we had gotten the keypad fully working.
我们已经完全实现了计算器的键盘的功能
All right, and we were talking a little bit about properties
我们将要讲一些关于 properties 和
and instant variables and how we had to initialize them.
实例变量相关的内容，以及如何去初始化它们
And so I'm gonna ask a question right at
我将要回答上次课快要结束时
the end of lecture, perfect timing.
提出的那个问题
What about the little outlet that we dragged out
为什么我们拖出的
that display UI label exclamation point, how come we
显示 UILabel 的 outlet 后面有个感叹号
didn't have to make that equal to something, to start.
以及为什么我们从一开始不需要将它赋值
And that's where this demo is gonna pick up.
我们将从这个地方继续上次的 Demo
Okay?
Okay.
Well, let's dive back into this demonstration,
好吧，让我们深入到演示中来，
where we left off.
接着我们上次讲的地方
Which it was this line of code, here.
上次我们在这行代码结束的
And, we had just talked about the fact that we have to
我们之前讲过我们必须
initialize all of our variables in a class,
在类中初始化我们的变量
in any class.
在任何类中都必须这样做
And, so that's why we need this equals falls here.
所以我们需要在这加个等号
They wanted the equal falls too but we needed it and yet
这里也需要等号赋值，但是
it didn't seem like we needed one here.
这里看起来并不需要等号赋值
And why was that?
为什么会是这样？
Well, it turns out that this right here,
其实，这里恰恰证明了
even though it doesn't quite look like one, is an optional.
即使它看起来不完全像之前那个，这是一个 optional
And, optionals automatically get equaled nil, given to you.
而且 optional 在你使用之前就赋了 nil
So, you don't actually have to put the equals nil here.
所以，其实你们并不需要在这里给它赋 nil
So that's why, so this one here is getting initialized.
这就是为什么这里已经初始化了
It's just being done automatically for you.
因为它都自动帮你做好了
But, let's talk about the look of this thing.
但是，我们来谈论一下这个东西的语法
It's got this exclamation point here.
在这里有个感叹号
And, if it were an optional,
如果它是一个 optional 类型的值
you'd be used to it having a question mark.
你们通常会在这里看到一个问号
For example, we look at this optional right here,
例如，我们来看这里这个 optional 的值
current title,
currentTitle,
you see it's String question mark not exclamation point,
你们将会看到这里 String 是问号而不是感叹号，
question mark.
这里是问号
So what's the difference between a question mark and
那么，这里的问号和感叹号之间
an exclamation point here?
有什么区别呢？
And the answer is,
答案是
it makes no difference to the actual type, it's still
对于实际类型而言它们没有区别，
an optional whose value here could be a UI label.
它仍然是一个 optional 的值，其值在这里可能是一个 UILabel 类型
But it matters on the usage of it.
但是它们在用法上是不一样的
And this is purely just kind of
这完全是编译器
a compiler helping you out thing, here.
帮你把这事做好了
But if we look at when I change this to
但是如果我们将这个感叹号改成问号
a question mark you see that some errors appear down here.
Xcode 将会在这里报出一些错误提示
So then let's click on one of these errors, like this one,
那么，让我们点击这其中的一个错误提示，比如说这个
and you can see the errors that UI label,
你们会看到这个错误提示说 UILabel?
question mark does not have a member named text.
没有一个叫 text 的成员变量
In other words you can't send text.
就是说，你不能向它发送 text 消息
UI label question mark,
UILabel? 顾名思义
which is what this is and that makes sense because UI label
是一个不确定值的变量，所以也就明白了 UILabel? 是
question mark is an optional and
optional 的类型
obviously an optional doesn't respond to text.
并且显而易见的，一个 optional 类型的变量不会响应 text 消息
UI labels do, but optionals don't.
UILabel 是这样的，但 optional 并不会这样
So, why are we getting this error now when we
那么回到问题，为什么之前不会报错
weren't getting it before.
而现在却出错了呢
And how would we get rid of this error?
我们又如何去避免这个错误呢？
Well, you could certainly get rid of
嗯，我们当然可以通过
this error by just putting an exclamation point here,
添加一个感叹号来避免这个错误
that would unwrap this optional.
它会对这个 optional 的变量进行解包
And now this would be an UI label right here and
那么现在这里刚好有一个 UILabel
we can send a text.
如果我们要想给它发送 text 消息
And we do the same thing up here.
就可以在这里也做同样的事情
We can unwrap it there and we can unwrap it there.
我们可以在这里对它进行解包，还有这里也要解包
And that gets rid of all of our errors.
这样就解决了所有的错误
But this kind of an interesting property in that
但是这里有个很有意思的属性 display
even though it's not initialized in
因为它并没有在
the very beginning of a class creation starts out
类最开始创建时初始化成 nil
as nil not set.
而是没有设值
As soon as as this user interface gets loaded up
一旦这个 UI 界面
by this new controller.
被右边的视图控制器加载了
Then this gets wired up, alright, so, that gets
那么它就会和代码连接起来，嗯对，只要连接起来
wired up, and this is set, and then this it's set forever.
这个变量就会被设置并初始化，那么它在整个类中就是永远初始化过了
So it's really, kinda would be sad if we actually,
但是，如果当我们每次解包时都要写感叹号
every time we used it had to unwrap it all the time.
那真是一件难过的事儿
So these kind of properties that.
所以这些很早前就被设置过属性变量
Get set very early, maybe not right at creation like
不一定要和这个一样，在创建时初始化
this one, but very, they get set very early, and
并且，它们设置的时间非常非常的早
then they stay set all the time.
之后一直保持着已设置的状态
You can, instead of
你也可以
putting a question mark in their decoration.
在声明的地方用一个问号来代替
We're talking about their decoration here.
我们将在这里谈论他们的声明
You can put an exclamation point.
你可以在这里加一个感叹号
And what that says is.
那么它要表达的意思是
This is just an optional, but
这虽然只是一个 optional 类型
always automatically unwrap it so that you don't have to
但它会自动对变量解包，从而就可以不用
put this exclamation point in here.
在这里加感叹号
So I take this exclamation point out.
所以，我把这里的感叹号删掉了
You can see, it's not generating any errors.
你们可以看到，它将不再报错
And it's still going to unwrap this display and
它将把 display 转化成
turn into a UI label.
UILabel
And.
而且
It's still gonna crash your program if for
它还是会由于
some reason the display were nil.
某些原因比如 display 是 nil 崩溃
If you tried to execute this code, that may
如果你执意要执行这段代码，那是
be impossible because this is the button sending those.
不可能的，因为这里是由按钮来发送这些的
So the button wouldn't be here if this hadn't gotten already
这个按钮不会在这里除非它被加载
loaded up in the set.
被赋值的时候
But if somehow you had some place in your controller or
但是如果在某种情况下你必须
you were accessing display before this UI got loaded.
在 UI 加载之前你要获取 display
It would crash, because it is unwrapping this,
它将崩溃，因为它还没有 unwrap
it's just that you don't have to put the explanation point,
你不需要在这里写感叹号
it's kinda like auto explanation point.
它会自动解析
And, this is called a implicitly unwrapped optional.
这个就叫做 unwrapped optional
Okay? Implicitly unwrapped optional.
有问题嘛？隐式 unwrapped optional
And it's really only useful for this kind, of property,
在这种情况下它对这类 property 来说有用
that's, set very early, and then stay set, forever.
在创建的时候就赋值，那么将一直被赋值
It's kind of sugar, really.
这是一种语法糖
Okay, so let's move on
好了，我们将继续
to the next button in our here.
接着下一个按钮
Which is going to be an enter button.
它就是 Enter 键
Now our calculator does not have an equals sign.
现在我们的计算器还没有等号
So you're probably used to calculators where you
你们也许通常会这样使用计算器
say six plus three then when you hit equals it shows you
6 乘以 3，然后你们按等号计算器展示
the result.
结果
This calculator is
我们的计算器会
a little more like a scientific calculator.
更像科学计算器
Has an enter key.
将没有等号按钮
And so, instead you put the numbers you want to add or
那么，你们按你们想相加的数字按钮或者
divide or multiply or whatever onto a stack and then when you
除以或者乘以无论什么都将会入栈，然后当你
press the operation keys it pulls them off the stack.
按下操作按钮的时候，数字将会出栈
So that looks like this, 6 enter 3 times.
比如这样 6 3 乘
Four, six, enter, three, enter, times.
4 6 enter 3 enter 乘
So the times is going to pull the six and
这个乘法操作符将会把 6 和
the three off the stack.
3 出栈
You could even go six, enter, five, enter, four, enter, and
你也可以按 6，enter，5，enter，4， enter，然后
then go times plus.
按乘以 加
That would multiply the top two on the stack and
它将会把栈顶的两个元素出栈
then add the last one on.
操作完再将加上栈顶的元素
So we need an enter key here for our calculator.
所以我们的计算器还是需要一个 Enter 键
Now, I'm gonna create that enter key in a way that's
现在，我将要通过这种方式创建一个 enter 键
actually gonna cause a problem for me in a moment, but
它虽然会引起一些问题，但是
I wanna show you how to resolve that very problem.
我将会展示给你们看如何解决这些问题
So I'm gonna create this enter key by copying and pasting.
那么，我将通过复制粘贴
This digit key right here.
这里的数字键来创建 Enter 键
And I'm just gonna put it in here.
那么我将会把这放在这里
Notice that I'm lining these,
我通过这些蓝色辅助线
blue lines up absolutely perfectly.
把这些连接起来
I don't want them to be, like it's lined up with that one,
我不想这按钮放这
but not that one or vice versa.
或者放这里
I want them perfectly lined up.
我希望它完全对齐
Cuz later I'm gonna spread these out over the whole UI
因为我待会要在整个 UI 中放大这些按钮
and if I haven't lined these up just absolutely perfectly
如果我没有将这些按钮对齐的话
then Expo's not gonna quite know what I want here in Xcode
我将不会知道它们会被
terms of the relationship between these.
Xcode 安排到哪里
All right so we don't want a three on here, we want to have
好了，我们不希望这个按钮上还是 3，所以我们需要修改一下
a,enter symbol so I'm gonna go up here to special characters.
一个 enter 的符号，我将输入一个特殊的符号
This is on in most Mac applications.
这个符号在很多的 Mac 应用中都有
You can go to the edit menu to get special characters.
你们可以从编辑菜单中获取这些特殊符号
And I'm going to search for
我想要搜索
this one actually, I think that's called a return.
这个特殊符号，我觉得它应该叫 return
Yeah. And these are just
是的，这些都是
Unicode characters right here.
Unicode 字符
And so I want this one that looks,
我想要这个
kind of like a return or enter key.
看起来像返回或者 enter 按钮的
So I have this.
好了，我找到了
And I'm gonna use the same mechanism we used before,
我将使用之前使用过的机制
which is CTRL+drag.
那就是 CTRL+drag
So I'm just gonna CTRL+drag out here.
那么我想 CTRL+drag 拖到这里
And, we're creating an action,
然后，我们创建一个 action
of course, cuz we want this button to send us a message.
当然，我们希望这个按钮给我们发个消息
I'm gonna call it"enter".
我将叫它 “enter”
That's what it is the enter key
那就是我们的返回键.
Now one thing is different about this one,
现在有一件事会有一点不同
if you'll remember when we wired this action up,
如果你记得当我们连接这个 action 的时候
we had the button that was sending it as an argument and
我们让这个按钮传递给我们一个参数
we don't want that this time.
但是我们这次不需要这么做
Because there's only one answer key we
因为这里只有一个返回键
really don't need to talk back to the answer key, so
我们并不需要让返回键传参，所以
we're going to say none right here.
我们在这里不需要参数
It also doesn't really matter about this type because we're
这里我们更不用关心它的类型，因为
not going to have an argument so
我们这里并不需要参数
it doesn't matter what this type is.
不用管它这里是什么类型
So connect that.
所以把它们连接
As you can see right here.
你们可以看这里
We have enter, and it has no arguments.
我们已经有一个 enter 键，没有参数的
Now, what are we gonna do inside enter?
那么现在，我们将在这个 enter 里做什么操作？
Well, the main thing we need to do is,
好吧，我们主要要做的是
put whatever number is in this display up here,
把 display 显示的数字
okay, onto our internal stack.
放入我们的栈中
So, we're gonna need
那么，我们需要
an internal stack, in a moment, here.
一个栈
Another thing we might wanna do, is.
另一件我们想做的事
Set usersInTheMiddleOfTypeingANumber to false.
设置 usersInTheMiddleOfTypeingANumber 为 false
Because we might have been typing a number, but
因为我们可能已经输入了一个数字
as soon as we hit enter, we're putting it on the stack.
但是，只要我们单击 enter 键，我们将把数字放入栈中
Next time we type a digit,
接下来我们再输入一个数字
we're going to be starting a new number.
我们将输入一个新的数字
All right, so we'll call that user in
好了，那么我们
the middle of typing falls there.
把它设置为 false 就好了
Now, let's go ahead and, and actually run this and
现在，让我们继续，运行这个
see how this is working.
看看它是怎么工作的
Because there's going to be a little problem here.
因为这里有个小问题
So, run this.
那么，先运行一下
Alright, so let's try eight, enter.
好了，让我们试一下输入 8，然后回车
Oh.Oh
What's that? Oh, my god.
那是什么？
Six, enter.
6，然后回车
Well it's, it's kind of working because after we
好吧，它能运行，但是我们
press enter the user is in the middle of typing numbers.
所按的回车也一起出现在数字里面了
Starts over.
重新开始
So that's good, but I had no intention for
所以这是好的，但是我并不想
this to be showing up on the end of my display.
让这个在最后显示出来
This little enter.
这个 enter
What the heck is that doing on there?
到底发生了什么？
Why is that happening?
为什么会发生这样的事
Let's take a look here.
让我们看看这里
The problem here, has to do with the messages being sent.
问题出在这里，在发消息之前
So, when we wire this up, that's good.
那么，当我们连接好了
We got enter.
我们已经有 enter 键了
The problem is that button also sends a appendDigit.
问题是那个按钮还传递 appendDigit 消息
That's because we copied and pasted this three, remember?
那是因为我们复制粘贴的 3 的按钮，记得么？
And the three sends appendDigit, until we copy and
而 3 按钮还传递了 appendDigit，直到我们复制
paste it.
粘贴了它
Now, this one sends, sends appendDigit.
现在 ，这个按钮发送了 appendDigit
So this is both.
而且这个也是
Okay, sending two.
传递了两次
Now, that's a common mistake to make.
这是一个很常见的错误
You know, you only think about that when you copy and
你们知道么，你们不会去想这些当你们复制
paste it.
粘贴它
And how do we fix this?
那么我们如何来修复这个问题？
Well if you right click, so
好了，如果你们右击一下
I'm going to right click on this button.
我将右键一下这个按钮
You'll get this window that comes up.
你们将会看到这个窗口
And it shows you all the connections from this
然后你们可以看到所有的连接
UI element to your code.
UI 元素到你们的代码
And you can see here both appendage and
你们可以看到这里都连接
enter are connected.
enter 键
The great thing is I can just click this little X right here
最棒的事我可以点击这里的 X 按钮
and it'll take this connection away.
然后这个连接就被取消了
So now I only have enter.
那么，现在我们只有 enter 键的连接了
So now if I go back here.
那么现在我们再回到之前的地方
See it's,
看这里
it's not sending appendDigit, it is sending enter.
它将不再发送 appendDigit，它只发送 enter
And you can do this right clicking for anything.
你们可以右键操作任何你们想做的
Like we need to do it for our label up here.
就像我们连接 label 一样
See there's the display connection we have right here.
看到没，这里显示了我们的连接
So don't forget right click to disconnect things.
不要忘记右键去除连接
Now if you forget about this and you don't do it.
现在，如果你们忘记这个，你们不要去操作它
Or maybe you have it wired to some thing that you change.
否则你们会连接一些你们修改的东西
For example, if we have accidentally put an argument
比如，我们需要传递一个参数
here to enter, if we had made it do descending button trick,
对于 enter 键来说，如果我们已经做过了
kind of like this.
像这样的
You can't just say, oh okay.
你们不能说好的
I'll fix that.
我将会修复它
I'll just delete that
我将会删除它的
Because that would not work because,
因为它将会不工作
enter with an argument is actually a different
因为带有参数的 enter 键
message than enter with no argument.
对于没参数的 enter 键来说发送的是不同的消息
And so, if you just deleted that when you were running
如果你们在运行的时候删除了这些
your program it would crash and
你的应用将会崩溃
it would say, couldn't send message enter colon.
它会说，不能发送消息 enter:
When you touch this button cause enter colon means enter
当你点击 enter 键的时候
with an argument, only for the purpose of this tour It doe-,
enter: 代表有参数，但是代码中看不到
we don't see enter colon in our code.
enter: 参数
That's just something that's, this story board here.
这就是 Story board 中发生的一些事
So if that happens, you need to right click on here and
那么如果这个发生了，你需要点击这里
disconnect the enter colon, that happened in there and
去除连接，然后再重新
then you just recontrol drag.
拖拽连接
When you recontrol drag it's nice it will.
当你重新连接好，它会变正常了
Kind of let you try to grab onto something, so
这里好像让你抓住什么东西一样
its easy to reconnect.
它很容易重新连接
OKay
All right, so now we want to actually implement enter here.
好了，那么现在我们在这里实现这个方法
We want to enter the guts of it.
我们开始着手实现它的内部
And so we are going to need another property here which is
我们需要在这定义另一个属性
going to be that
它将是用
internal stack that these numbers are going to go on.
一个内部的栈去存储这些数字
And so that's gonna be a var just like
所以它会是一个变量，就像
this var up here that we've created and
我们刚创建的这个变量
I'm call it operand stack that's a good name for it.
我叫它 operandStack，不错的名字
And it's gonna have a type,
它会有一个类型
it's type is going to be an array and
它的类型是数组
just like in other languages like Java when you specify,
就像在其他语言中，比如说 Java
when you create an array type you have to specify.
当你创建一个数组，你必须指明它的类型
What kind of thing is in the array.
表明数组里面存储的是什么
And so, I'm gonna put doubles in my array.
因此，我打算在里面存放 double 元素
And that's, even though you might say, well we can't
嗯 也许你会说，好吧我们并不能
enter doubles, because these are all integers, basically.
输入 double，因为这里大都是些整数
But if I were to say, 3 enter 6 divide, I get .5.
但是假如我说，输入 3 除以 6，我会得到 0.5
So than a double would appear.
这样就出现了一个 double 的结果
So that's why I'm going to use double.
这就是我为什么要使用 double 的原因
Now, you can see that we've got this error up here again.
现在，你们可以看到这里又弹出了这个错误
It says stored property operandStack does not
上面说 “存储的 property operandStack 并没有
have initial value.
一个初始值”
So we have to give this an initial value.
所以我们得赋给它初始值
So I'm going to give this an initial value of
我准备把初始值赋为
an empty array.
一个空的数组
So now you're seeing for the first time how you actually.
现在你们第一次看到如何
Create an instance of a class or of a data type.
创建一个类或者数据类型的实例
And you do that just by specifying the type and
你只需要在这指明类型
then use parenthesis.
然后加上圆括号
Now, we're not,
现在，我们没有
again we haven't talked about initializers.
我们还没有讨论过初始化方法（initializer）
A class or
一个类或者
a data structure can have multiple initializers.
一种数据类型可以有许多初始化方法
Some of them might have arguments in here.
其中的一些可能会需要参数
But most, if it's possible they'll allow you to
但大多数情况，如果允许，你都可以
create them with no arguments and in a case on
利用没有参数的初始化方法来创建对象
array，it's very obvious what to do.
对于这里的数组，很明显
No arguments just creates an empty array right,
不需要参数，只要创建一个空的数组
with no elements in it.
数组内部不需要任何的元素
Now, one thing I want to talk about is this right here.
现在，我想说一下这里的这个东西（第一个 Array）
This type, you know?
这个东西，你们知道吗
It's kind of annoying that we have to type this and
你会觉得很烦，如果在前面定义了类型
then we have to type it right again.
然后在后面又得定义一遍
And the answer is, we don't have to do that,
而事实上，我们并不需要这么做
because in swift, swift is very strongly typed.
因为 Swift 是强类型语言
You know there's all the variables, but
所有的变量
the properties are strongly typed.
属性都是强类型的
But they, there's also a lot of type inference.
而且 Swift 可以做很多的类型推断
So swift can infer.
类型推断
This type in the exact same way that digit had no type and
比如说这里的 digit 并没有声明类型
it inferred it from here.
但它可以从后面的语句中推断出来
OperandStack, we don't have to specify they type, and
operandStack，我们并不需要指明它的类型，因为
it can infer it from here.
可以从这里的初始化方法中推断出来
And if we option click on operandStack you'll see that
如果我们按住 option 点击 operandStack，你会看到
indeed, it's figured out that that's an array of double.
它确实可以辨识出这是一个 double 类型的数组
And in fact,
事实上
putting the type in here is considered bad form.
在这里指明类型被认为是不好的书写形式
If it can be inferred, you should let it infer, so,
如果可以推断出类型，你就应该让它（编译器）自己去推断，所以
if we didn't have this bool up here we shouldn't that either,
拿这里的 Bool 来说，我们其实不需要声明类型
because, false, and true are, can only be bool values so,
因为 false 和 true 只可能是 Bool 类型的
we're gonna take that off as well.
所以我们也可以把它去掉
Okay, so, now, our operand
好了，那么现在，我们这里有操作符栈
stack right here what do we wanna do with it?
我们打算把怎么处理它呢？
Well, when we press enter, we just want to append.
嗯，我们按下回车，然后我们想要 append
So, append.
所以，append
This is actually the first time we're sending an actual
事实上这是我们第一次发送一条
message to an object looks just like when we
消息给一个对象，但是这种写法就像
accessed a property.
获取了一个属性一样
The dot and it's just the name of the method that we're
输入点号，然后就出现了我们想要在这个数组上
trying to invoke in our arrays.
调用的方法名字
Just an array, an array method right here called a append.
这是一个叫做 append 的数组方法
I think you see the arguments as newElement: T.
我想你们看到了这个参数 —— newElement: T
This : T means it has to be of this type.
这个 : T 意味着它必须是这个类型
Type of things in the array so this has to be a double.
这个数组里面东西的类型，所以它必须是一个 double
So that's kind of a problem, cuz really what I want to
这也是一个问题，因为事实上我想要在
append onto my stack is what's up here in this display text.
我的栈上附加的是，这里 display.text 的内容
And, you know, I'd like to say something along the lines
然后在这行输入
of display.text.
display.text
Okay? But what type is this?
好吧，它的类型是什么呢？
I can type display.text.（type of display.text？？）
display.text 的类型
Now that's not String.
它不是 String
That is an optional.
它是一个 optional String
Remember that display.text is an optional.
记住这里的 display.text 是一个 optional String
So we can unwrap it even though
所以我们可以把它拆包，但
that's not gonna solve the problem.
这并不能解决问题
This is still a String and
这仍是一个 String
you're still seeing an error here.
你们还是可以看到这里有一个错误
This saying 'String' is not convertible to double [COUGH].
上面写着 “String 不可以转化为 Double”
Because we're supposed to be putting doubles in
因为我们本应把 Double 放入
this array putting Strings.
这个数组而不是 String
So, we have a problem here.
所以，我们在这有个问题
We have somehow to convert this String into a double so
我们得用某种方式把 String 转化成 Double 以便
we can put it on this stack.
我们把它放入栈中
I'm gonna use this opportunity.
我要借用这个机会，
Just show you another feature which we
向你们展示另一个特性，我们
call Computed Properties.
称之为计算型属性（Computed Properties）
So I'm gonna create another property display value and
所以我要在这里创建另一个属性 displayValue,
it's gonna be a Double.
它是一个 Double
And what I want this to be equal to is, I always want it
然后我想让它等于，我想让它
to be whatever's in this display converted to a double.
等于这里的显示转化成 Double 的值
Okay? And I want to
好了，然后我想
be able to set it or get it so
有办法对它进行设值以及取值，以便
I'm gonna be able to get the value of this double.
我能够取到这个 Double 的值
I just want to be able to set it as a double and
我想把它设值成一个 Double 然后
have it turn into text.
把它转化成文本
Well, that kind of
好吧，这种类型的
property really is tied to some data somewhere else.
属性实际上是与其他地方的某些数据绑定的
So, I don't ever want to set it equal to some initial value
所以，我不想把它设成某个初始值
or something.
还是其他的什么
Really, I want it to always be calculated and we can do that.
我想让它总是由计算得到的，而我们在 Swift 里可以做到
Instead of saying equals something,
与其输入 “这个变量等于什么什么”
you just put curly braces after.
你只需要在后面输入，花括号
And you say, get, and we say, set.
然后写下 get ，再写 set
Okay?
就好了
And inside here we are gonna compute the value of this.
然后在这里面，我们要对它的值进行计算了
Which is we are gonna convert this display text
这将会把这里的 display.text 转化成
to a double and then inside here, we are, someone said,
Double，然后在这里，我们要，要让
display value equal something and we are going to
displayValue 等于什么，我们要做的是
somehow compute, not really compute it, but.
想办法能够计算它，并不是真正计算某一个特定的值，而是
We're gonna de, decide, what code we need to put that
我们要决定我们需要什么样的代码能够
number that they tried to set the display value to in here.
决定 displayValue 在这里被设成什么值
'Kay, so let's do the set side first.
好吧，那么让我们先来写 set 方法
It's actually a little simpler.
这其实会简单一些
Inside this set,
在 set 方法里
there's a magic variable called new value.
会有一个叫作 newValue 的变量
It doesn't, it's not purple for some reason, but.
因为某些原因，它的高亮并不是显示为紫色的
New value in this, this is the new value.
这里的 newValue 就是将要被设置的那个值
So if someone says somewhere in our code,
如果说某些人在我们的代码里
display value equals five,
让 displayValue 的值等于 5
this new value will have the five.
那这个 newValue 就会是 5
And so all I really wanna do
我所想做的
here is say display text equals the new value.
就是在这，让 display.text 等于 newValue
But again, of course this is an optional String.
但同样的问题，这是个 optional String
You can't set it to a double because displayValue equals
你不能把它设成一个 Double，因为 displayValue 等于
five, this new values going to be a double.
5，这个 newValue 将会是一个 Double
But we know how to convert something to a String by
但是我们知道如何把它转化成 String，只需要写上
using backlash parenthesis.
反斜线，圆括号
And this is the same thing we did when we
这其实和我们
printed out [COUGH] our digit up here.
之前输出的 digit 的过程是一样的
We just use the back slash parenthesis.
我们只需要写上反斜线和圆括号
It tries to convert this thing inside here,
它会试着在这里转化这个东西
which is a double into a String of doubles.
把一个 Double 转化成 String
You know how to do that themselves.
你知道该怎么做了
And so bingo, we've got our display text and
没错 我们有了自己的 display.text
that's all that necessary.
这就够了
also, every time someone sets this displayValue and then we're
而且，每次有人设 displayValue 的值时
clearly not in the middle of typing a number anymore.
很明显，我们知道，此时我们不在是在输入数字的状态了
[INAUDIBLE] Say that.
把这个状态设置成 false
[INAUDIBLE] All right, what about the getting?
好吧，那关于取值呢？
Now in the getting all we have to do is
在取值方法中，我们所要做的就是
return this display value.
返回 displayValue
So it's do something to calculate what this
所以这里需要做的就是计算
display value is here.
这里的 displayValue
And then return it.
然后返回它
Now this one I'm not gonna take time to go
这次我不会花时间去
through the details here.
详细说明细节
And actually I've made it an extra credit item that you can
实际上我把它算作一个给你们去做的额外加分项
do, which requires you to figure out
需要你们利用文档，去搞清楚我在这写的代码
what I'm gonna type here using the documentation.
是什么意思
But I'm not going to explain it here.
但现在我不想给出代码的解释
I'm gonna use a class that's in this number formatter.
这里，我要在使用一个叫作 NumberFormatter 的类
I'm actually gonna create one and
我先创建一个实例，然后
I'm gonna use a method on it called number from String.
使用它的 numberFromString 方法
And I'm gonna give it this String which is
然后我会把这个字符串传给它，
the display values text, unwrapped of course.
这个字符串也就是 display.text，当然得拆包
The result is acting optional so I'm gonna unwrap that.
它的返回值是一个 optional String，所以我继续要把它拆包
And then I'm gonna get the double value of the thing I
然后我再得到它返回的 Double 值
get back [COUGH].
Number gives me this kind of generic number so
Number 给了我这种泛型的数字，所以
I am gonna take it and turn it into a double.
我把它转化成一个 Double
So there we go.
好了
So you can go the next spread and
你们可以继续下一步了
look at that later if you want.
如果你想的话，以后再考虑它
But surprising to say we
高兴的是，我们
now have a property display value that when we set it and
现在有了一个 displayValue 的属性，当我们设值和取值时
get it, it's gonna be setting and getting.
我们调用了自定义的 set 和 get 方法
It has a String here, so that is really convenient.
UILabel 这里是一个字符串，所以也挺方便的
Especially for
尤其是这里
right here, where we wanna say display value.
其实我们想传入的是 displayValue
'Kay?
明白了吗？
So let's see the double.
让我们回头检查一下，Double
No problem.
没错
We're pinning that onto operandStack.
我们把它附到 operandStack 上了，而 operandStack 里的元素也是 Double 的
So let's print in our operandStack here.
接下来，让我们把 operandStack 在这打印出来
Just so, I mean we can do the same thing here, operandStack.
就像这样，一样的方式，\(operandStack)
Okay?
没问题吧？
And this worked because operandStack is an array, and
这种方式可行是因为 operandStack 是一个数组
arrays know how to turn themselves into Strings.
数组知道如何把它们自身转化成字符串
You'll see how they do that in the console in a moment here.
你一会儿就会在控制台输出里看到它们是怎么做到的了
So let's go ahead and
所以，我们继续
see if our application is actually putting things on
来看看我们的应用是否真的正确地能够把东西放到
our stack properly here.
我们的栈里
[NOISE] All right.
好的
Let's try here.
我们尝试着在这里
Let's try 56 enter.
在这里输入 56
And look, operandStack equals 56 doing good.
看，operandStack 是等于 56，运行正常
Seven enter.
输入 7
All right, 56.0 and 7.0.
好的，56.0 和 7.0
So, you can see that arrays turn themselves into Strings
所以你们看到了数组是如何把自身转化成字符串的
by doing open square bracket and then they turn each of
在这个方括号里，它们把自身的每个
their elements into Strings and separated by commas.
元素转化成字符串并以逗号分隔
Now this is good.
这个就搞定了
So we got our operand, operandStack building here.
我们这的 operandStack 就创建好了
So all we need to do is have some times, and plus, and
接下来我们现在需要做的就是要有乘法，加法和
minus buttons, etc.
减法之类的按钮
I'm gonna put them right here.
我准备把它们放在这个位置
That will operate on these items uh, on the stack.
它在在这些项上进行运算，准确的说是在栈上
So, if I pressed plus right now,
所以，如果我现在按下加
it would pull the seven and the eight off the stack.
它就会把 7 和 8 从栈中取出来（pop）
Add them together, it would be 15.
把他们相加，得到 15
Show that 15 here, and
然后在这里显示 15
it actually will put the 15 back on the stack.
实际上，15 会被放回到栈里（push）
So then, we'd have 56 and 15 on our stack.
然后，我们的栈里就有了 56 和 15
Then we could, maybe.
接着我们就可以
Plus those together and we wanted by it plus again.
再运行一次加法，把它们加到一起
All right?
没错吧？
[COUGH] Okay.
好的
So how are we gonna do that?
所以我们应该怎么做呢？
Well, we would make our buttons here.
嗯，我们将把这些运算符的按钮放在这个位置
And I'm gonna make the buttons again by copying and
我通过复制粘贴数字按钮来
pasting a digit button.
创建这些个运算符按钮
But this time I know about that problem,
但是这次我已经知道会出现哪个问题了
so right off the bat I'm gonna right click on it.
所以我马上就右键点击刚才粘贴的按钮
And disconnect appendDigit: it.
然后取消和 appendDigit 方法的关联
Okay? So
好的，那么
now this button sends no messages, yet anyway.
现在，这个按钮就不会发送任何消息了
And then we could put a type on here.
然后我们要在这上面设置一个运算符
So here I'm gonna have my all my operations buttons use
这里我要让所有的运算符按钮都使用
mathematical symbols so if we go down here to math symbols.
数学符号，而不是编程中的那些运算符号，所以我们看这里的 Math Symbols
See there's a bunch of math symbols here.
看这里有好多数学符号
So let's do times, right here,
现在，我们来给乘法设置符号
first, we'll put times right there, and we can wire it up.
首先，把乘法放到这，然后我们可以把它与代码链接在一起
I'm just gonna hold that Ctrl and drag out here.
按住 Ctrl 然后拖动这里来
We're gonna call this action method.
我们把这个 Action 称作
Operate.
operate 方法
And because I'm gonna have multiple operation buttons and
因为会有许多运算按钮，所以
they're all going to send operate.
他们都会发送 operate 消息
Just like I did with append digit,
就像数字按钮和 appendDigit 方法链接在一起一样
I am going to use the sender.
我要使用这个 sender
So I'm gonna be very careful to change this any
所以我得仔细地
object to be button.
把 Sender 的类型从 AnyObject 改成 UIButton
Do not forget that.
不要忘记这点
'Kay, so action, we are gonna have it sender.
Sender 类型
UIButton.
为 UIButton
Call it operate.
Action 名字为 operate
There it is.
就是这些设置了
That's method doing operate.
这就是做操作符运算的方法
We can copy and paste this button now, right?
我们现在可以复制粘贴这个按钮了
We got this one, so
我们用乘法的这个
let's copy and paste and make some more of these.
复制粘贴，然后重复，重复
We'll start out with four of them, let's say.
我们先粘贴出 4 个运算符
'Kay?
Let's get back our special characters here.
我们回到特殊符号这里
[COUGH] All right, so let's make this one be divide.
我们来把第二个设置为除法
Let's make this one plus.
第三个，加法
And this one be minus.
最后一个，减法
All right.
好了
So we've got these buttons [COUGH].
操作符按钮就完成了
And they're all sending, if we look at this here,
它们都会发送，如果我们看这里
they're all sending operate.
它们都会发送 operate 消息
Luckily, they're not sending anything except operate, so
幸运的是它们并不会发送运算之外的东西
that's good.
这样就好
And when they send operate, we're gonna figure out
当它们发送同样的 operate 消息的时候，我们要搞清楚
which one is sending it by the same exact way we did above.
发送消息的对象是哪一个
We're gonna say what is the sender's current title?
也就是说，Sender 的 currentTitle 是什么？
We're gonna unwrap it.
我们要把它拆包
So operation here is gonna be a String.
这里的 operation 是一个 String
And it's going to tell us the title of the buttons so
它会告诉我们按钮的 title，所以
we know which one to use there.
我们就知道了该怎么处理
Now I'm gonna show you a control flow operator here in
现在我要给你们展示 Swift 中的控制流符号
Swift that's very powerful, much more powerful than
它非常强大，比其他语言中的强大多了
this operator is in other languages.
And also very, very important to swift.
而且对 Swift 语言自身来说是很重要的
I'm only gonna show you the simplest usage of it here, but
这里我只会向你们展示控制流符号最简单的用法
you're gonna see on Monday's demonstration and
你们会在周一的展示和
later in the quarter how important this operator is.
接下来的学习中感受到它的强大之处
But, it's switch, okay, and
switch
switch looks like switch in other languages, like C.
它和其他语言中的 switch 看起来很像，比如说 C
You switch on something.
你在某个变量上使用 switch
In this case I'm gonna switch on this String.
在这里，我会在这个字符串上 switch
This is the String.
字符串 operation
Then you just specify the case of each thing.
然后你指明所有 case 情况
So for example here I have a case.
举例来说，有一个 case
Let's do the multiply.
进行乘法
Okay, so we've got multiply case right here.
那我们就在这里创建一个乘法 case
And then we just put the code that we want here
接着我们只需把做乘法的代码
for multiply.
放到这里
And we'd do that for all the other cases here.
接着对其他的操作符 case 也这么做
So let's copy and paste.
复制粘贴一下
And we'll do this be our divide case.
这个是除法 case
And we'll have this be our plus case and
这个是加法 case
we'll have this be our,
在这里是减法 case
make sure we're doing the same here, plus case.
我们在复制粘贴减法 case 的时候
Again, you've got to be a little careful here.
你需要仔细一点
You know, this minus is slightly different from this
因为左边的减号符号和
minus which might be slightly different than the minus
右边的减号符号有轻微的不同
you type with the keyboard.
右边的减号符号是你从键盘上输入的那种
So, when you're putting the symbols here,
所以，当你们在这放置符号的时候
you wanna use exactly the same symbols here in your case.
你们要确保代码中的和 Storyboard 中使用的是同一个
Now, one thing about switch on Swift though is it
关于 Swift 中的 switch，要注意的一件事就是
absolutely requires that you have every case covered.
你必须确保覆盖所有情况（case）
Now since this is a String, obviously can't have case of
由于这是一个字符串，你显然不可能
every single String in the universe.
穷举每一种情况
That is almost infinite, but luckily there,
通常是无限多的，但是很幸运的是
you can take defaults and just break out of the switch.
可以在 default 后，使用 break 来跳出 switch
That means if it's not one of these cases by default just
也就意味着，如果不是 default 之前列举的那些情况
break out of the switch.
就会跳出 switch
You could put code here as well,
这不是说代码不能放在 default 中
but breaking out of it is what we wanna do in our case.
只是在这里，我们想要从 switch 中 break 而已
now, in here, we're just going to put the code for multiply.
现在，在这里，我们输入与乘法相关的语句
So, what do we need to do for multiply?
那么，乘法需要做些什么?
For the moment, I'm gonna comment this out.
我会暂时将这部分注释掉
I'm gonna use command, slash,
使用 ⌘ + / 键来注释
which is a really nice feature.
这个快捷键的确称得上是一个很不错的功能
You do command slash.
按下 ⌘ + / 键之后
And then command slash again, to uncomment.
再次按下 ⌘ + / 键来取消给代码注释
[INAUDIBLE] real quick cuz I just wanna focus on times.
这里我想专注于乘法操作的代码
Now any time I press any operator,
任何时候，点击任何操作符
I probably wanna give the user an automatic enter.
我希望自动给用户按下 enter 按钮
That's so that six enter, three enter,
也就是 6，enter，3，enter
times is the same as six enter three times.
乘法，等价于 6 乘以 3
Okay, so six enter three times is gonna do an automatic enter
这里，6，enter，3，乘法会自动在
on that three.
在 3 之后输入一个 enter
Cuz obviously, I intend to have six and
显然在这种情况下，我想让 6 和
three be multiplied in that case.
3 相乘
So for all of these operations, I going to say,
所以，对于所有的操作符的 Action
if the users in the middle of typing a number.
如果用户正在输入一个数字（userIsInTheMiddleOfTypingANumber 为 true）
Then hit enter for me, right here.
那么，我要自动帮用户输入一个 enter，即调用 enter()
Okay, so [COUGH] what do we need to do in
接下来，我们
this specific case of times?
需要乘法在这里做什么？
Well, really we just want to set our display value.
我们需要在这里对 displayValue 设值
Remember we have our nice display value down here.
还记得吗？我们自定义了 displayValue 的取值和设值方法
And we can do setting as well as getting.
取值和设值方法
So I set that display value.
因此，我在这里需要做的是
Up here.
设值
Equal to multiplying the top two things on this stack.
displayValue 等于将栈顶的两个数相乘
So I can actually remove something off our stack.
因此，我可以从栈里移除一些元素
We're representing our stack as an array.
我们可以使用一个数组代表栈结构
Of course, they are stacked as an array.
而且，这里确实是使用了一个数组来表示栈结构
And so a stack is something you push things on,
栈是一种数据结构，你可以压入元素到栈里
you pop things off.
也可以从栈里弹出元素
And with an array, we're just gonna add something there at
用数组实现的话，我们只需要
the end to push something on, and
在数组的末尾添加一个元素，来模拟元素的入栈操作
that will just remove it from the end to pop it off.
在数组的末尾移除一个元素，来模拟元素的出栈操作
So there's a nice.
没问题吧？
All right. This is an array, right?
好的，这是一个数组
Operand stacks.
数组名称是 operandStack
There's a nice method called remove last.
有个方法叫 removeLast()
And if we option click on remove last, you'll see here
如果在 removeLast 方法上按住 option 键并单击
that it removes an element from the end of the array.
可以看到说明：从数组的末尾移除一个元素
Now, it does require a count greater than zero.
这个方法需要数组的元素个数大于零
So if our array were empty this would crash our program.
如果数组是空的话，移除元素会导致程序崩溃
So let's put a little protective thing here.
所以，在这里做一些保护性的措施.
If the operand stacks.
如果 operandStack
There's a nice property here called Count on that.
operandStack 变量有一个属性叫做 count
It is greater or
如果它大于或者
equal to two actually because multiply takes two operand so
等于 2，因为乘法需要 2 个操作数
there better two things on this stack.
所以栈中至少需要有 2 个元素
Then we can do this and so
那么我们可以把这取出来的栈顶元素
we're gonna multiply that by and remove the next one.
相乘上第二次调用 removeLast() 所取出来的栈顶元素
Okay?
明白了吗？
So here we got-
这样的话
We're just taking the last two things off of this stack by
我们从栈中移除最顶上的两个元素
removing them from the end of the array and
通过从数组中移除最后的元素（removeLast 方法）
just assigning it to display value.
将运算结果赋值给 displayValue 变量
And we probably also want to do an enter here,
接着，我们希望在这里输入一个 enter()
because [COUGH] if I go six enter three times,
如果用户按下了 6，enter，3，乘
well then I want to be able to say then nine plus and
然后接着，用户按下了 9，加
have it add onto the six times three.
这代表着在原来运算的结果上加 9
So we want an automatic enter here, as well.
所以，这里需要一个自动点击 enter 的操作
Okay?
明白了吗？
So, that's pretty much all we need to do here.
这大概就是我们所有需要在这里做的了
Let's go ahead and run this, see how this works.
让我们运行这个应用，看看它是否正常工作
And so, six enter, or three enter, six enter.
我们尝试输入 3，enter，6，enter
Now we've got them both on the stack.
我们可以从控制台看到它们已经在栈上了
Times and you can see we put our 18 here.
然后我让它们相乘，可以看到结果是 18
It also put it back on the stack and
18 这个结果也被放入了栈中
we can say five times.
我们再输入 5，乘
That put a five on the stack and
这个操作将 5 放入栈中,
then multiplied them, took it off.
将它们两个从栈中移除并相乘，返回结果
So that's working nicely.
程序正常运行
[COUGH] Now what about our-
现在
Other buttons, here.
我们的其他的运算符按钮
We gonna make those work.
我们想要让它们正常工作
Let's do that.
让我们继续完成
Now, they do a very similar thing, here.
其他的运算符功能和乘法的功能是十分相似的
So, one temptation would be to just copy here.
所以，我们复制乘法的这部分代码
Let's uncomment these out.
先取消这部分的注释
And then just paste it, repeatedly.
然后重复粘贴
So, put it there.
放到这些位置
There, there and then just changes times in here.
只需要修改这里的乘号
D note to plus for example on this one.
把这个换成个加号
But his is pretty messy code, look at all this
但是，这样的代码看起来很乱
incredible amount of duplicating code, in here.
这里有大量的重复的代码
We really probably wouldn't to write our code like this.
我们不希望代码写成这样子
People would think we were terrible programmers I
如果写成这样，别人会认为我们是很糟糕的程序员
think if we did that.
Really what would be nice is if we had some,
什么样的代码看起来会不错呢？
could write some kind of function.
那就是如果我们可以把这些重复的代码写成函数
Maybe we could call it perform operation or
然后给函数起名为 perfomOperation
something like that.
或者类似意思的名字
And if the argument to that function.
至于函数的参数
Remember that arguments have names.
需要注意的是，函数参数也是有名字的
Here's the name.
这就是参数的名字
And then we have the type.
然后是参数的类型
The argument were something which basically was this
这里的参数是
little operation in here, or
这里的运算操作符
some sort of function that would do this operation.
或者是能够完成运算操作符操作的函数
So if this could be some sort of function that
如果可以把这些重复代码写成函数的话
would be cool.
看起来就很棒了
Then, maybe we could.
接下来
I take this code out of here, put it in here.
将这段代码移动到这个位置
Let's call it perform not pre-form, perform operation.
并起名为 performOperation
[LAUGH] Put it in here and
放到这里
instead of doing, you know, multiply here.
这里注意，我们把乘号改掉
Let's go ahead and we can do this operation some how.
用其他的方式来进行运算
I guess, well maybe operation,
可能是某个叫 operation 函数
call it like a function with two arguments here.
接受两个参数
Okay. That would be
好了，这样看起来很不错了
cool because we'd be sharing, you know, this check.
因为我们复用了这段代码，复用了这个判读
We'd be sharing this enter.
复用了这 enter 方法
[COUGH] We'd be sharing the removal of the operator.
复用了从栈中弹出两个元素的方法
We'd be sharing the same display value.
复用了 displayValue 变量
We'd be kind of sharing a lot of code here and
通过这样，复用了大段的代码
then up here if we could just do something like,
至于在上面的 case 结构，我们只需要像这样
perform operation, and, somehow, specify,
调用函数 performOperation，并且
multiply, as the operation we wanted to do here.
指定函数参数 multiply
And then we wouldn't need all this stuff here, right?
原来的那一大段代码就都不需要了，明白了吗？
So this is gonna be cool.
看起来很不错
Now, can we do this?
有人会质疑，我们可以这样做吗？
Well, yes, the answer is we can.
答案是当然可以
And so, types, functions.
参数类型，函数
Can be types in Swift, just like any other type.
函数在 Swift 里可以被当做一种类型，就像 Swfit 中其他的类型一样
So, you know, we have a double here, oops, double.
你知道，这里需要一个 Double 类型的参数
That's a type.
就是这个类型
You can also have a function type.
当然也可以有一个函数类型的参数
So how do you specify a function type?
那么，怎么指定一个函数类型呢？
Well multiple I or
无论是 multiple
whatever function I'm about to perform here.
或者是任何其他我想要在这里执行的函数
This is a function that takes two doubles as arguments.
这样的函数需要两个 Double 类型的参数
And it returns a double.
并且，它的返回值类型也是一个 Double 类型
So, I can just say, I want operation to be
所以我在这里输入
a function that takes two doubles and returns a double.
我想要 operation 是一个函数，带两个 Double 类型参数，返回 Double 类型
I can express that right here.
这就是我要表达的
This is a type, the type of this.
这就是函数类型的定义
Argument right here that you can click on and say yeah
在函数的名称上按住 option 单击
that type is double takes two doubles and returns a double.
你可以看到信息：2 个 Double 类型的参数，1 个 Double 类型的返回值
So, just simple as that.
就是这么简单
So all we need now is a function here
我们目前已知的就是，这里有一个函数
called multiply that takes two doubles and
这个函数名称为 multiply，带 2 个 Double 类型的参数
returns a double and does multiplication.
返回 1 个 Double 类型的返回值，函数功能是完成乘法操作
So we could go down here and say okay multiply and
接下来我们在下面输入 multiply 函数的代码
you'll have op1 which is double and op2.
第一个参数 op1，Double 类型，第二个参数 op2
[COUGH] A double and it returned the double.
Double 类型，返回一个 Double 类型
And it's just return one times out two.
返回值是 op1 乘以 op2 的结果
Okay?
对吗？
And that worked great.
一切都很好
Back out again so we can see if this actually works.
回到上面，看它是否真的可以正常运行
But there's no errors here.
没有任何错误
Right? It seems to work.
对么？看起来很正常
Multiply seems to be a function to take the $2 and
multiply 就是一个接受两个参数，返回一个 Double 这样的函数
turns it double.
And that's what this argument here is and
这就是 performOperation 的参数
I'm passing it along.
我将 multiply 传入
It should all work so let's give it a try.
这一切都没有问题，所以应该是可行的，那么我们来试一下吧
So here we go as six enter.
输入 6，enter
54 times and sure enough it's working it.
54，乘以，输出结果是 324.0，没问题
It's doing that multiplication.
完成了乘法操作，我们可以在控制台输出里看到
Works great and so what about all of our other cases here?
乘法做的不错，其他的 case 情况呢？
Well we would just need to take this same.
只需要也像 multiply 这样做
Piece of code right here and put it for all of them.
我们在所有的 case 情况下粘贴 performOperation(multiply)
And of course we need a divide method, so we have to
当然了，我们需要除法函数
come down here, and copy and paste that, and make divide.
所以把这里 multiply 改名为 divide，同时，然后复制 multiply 的实现并在它的下面粘贴更名为 divide
Oh wait a second,
稍等
this is starting to be just as bad as I had before.
这又像之前看起来的那样糟糕了
Having to make all these extra functions, multiply and
需要这些额外的函数：乘法
divide and all that.
除法，等等
Well [COUGH] it turns out it's so
事情上
common to pass functions as arguments in Swift, that it
在 Swift 中，将函数作为参数传递是很常见的
allows you to put a function like multiply right in
允许你在这里传递一个，例如 multiply 的函数
here without having to create a separate function like this.
而不需要单独创建一个函数
And all you do is you just pick it up.
所有你需要做的是就是选中函数的这块部分
So I'm just going to cut that from down here and
从这里剪切
I'm going to paste it right in here.
粘贴到上面这里来
The only thing you have to change syntactically when you
唯一需要在语法上做的改变的就是
do that is this curly brace, okay.
这里左侧的花括号
Instead of being after the declaration of
不是之前在声明函数的参数和返回值之后
the arguments in the return value, it needs to be before.
而是在这两者之前
So, you move the curly brace before.
所以，你把花括号放到前面去
And then where the curly brace was,
之前这里是小括号的位置
you gonna put in, the word in.
添加一个单词 in
And so that allows us to just.
这里我们稍微调整下
Come and do that again to eliminate some of our errors.
现在把这些代码都注释掉，不要让程序有错误
And we can get rid of function multiply down here.
然后，我们就可以移除这里的 func multiply 了
So that allows me to just put that multiplier right in here.
以上这些步骤就允许我们把乘法的实现
Right in line.
放在 case 情况的一行里面
Right as the argument to this function.
直接给 performOperation 函数传递一个函数参数
And this things kind of wacky.
对于一些不了解的人来说
For those of you who don't know it,
这种方式看起来略古怪
user programming languages that allow this kind
但在一些编程语言中，这种写法是允许的
of thing to happen are called closures.
这样的情况称之为闭包（closure）
It basically allows you to put a function right in there.
它允许你在这里放置一个函数
And this, okay here, looks okay, I mean we can certainly
好的，这样就看起来不错
you know, now we can copy and paste this and put it here.
下面就可以复制，粘贴这段代码
You know, here and
放在除法的 case 这里
change this and put it here and change this.
然后将 divide 改成我们复制的代码，以此类推，加法、减法也是如此
But it can even be better than this.
但是，我们可以进一步改进
So we know that Swift is really good at
我们知道 Swift 引以为傲的
something called type inference.
一个特性称就是类型推断
Where I can kinda figure out the type,
也就是我可以通过上下文（context）来
of something, from the context.
推断某个东西是什么类型的
And you can do the same thing here.
这里你也可以这么做
Because its looking at performOperation.
因为 Swift 的编译器看到这里的 performOperation
It knows you're calling perform operation.
它知道你在调用 performOperation
It knows this argument is a function that takes two
它知道这个函数的参数
doubles and returns a double.
是 2 个 Double 类型，返回值是 1 个 Double 类型的
So you really don't have to specify all the types in here.
所以在这里，我们不需要指定参数和返回值的类型
Cuz it knows all of this.
因为编译器知道这些事情
So you can actually get rid of all these type decorations,
所以，你可以删除这些参数类型声明
right here, even the return.
甚至是返回值类型也一样可以省去
And, again, seeing no warnings, no errors.
可以看到，删除后，没有任何警告和错误
It knows that this has to be a double, and
它知道这个第一个参数必须是一个 Double 类型的
this has to be a double.
第二个参数也必须是一个 Double 类型的
Because it knows you're calling perform operation.
因为它知道你调用的是 performOperation
So it knows the argument to that is like that.
所以，它知道函数的参数是什么类型的
Okay, and you can even make this look a little nicer.
好的，那么我们可以对我们的代码进行进一步的改进
We can move this all up onto one line.
把这个闭包写在一行里面
Really nice for readability here.
看来起更具有可读性、更优雅
But, we can actually do even better than this,
事实上，还能有更好的写法
because Swift knows that perform operations argument
因为 Swift 的编译器知道这个函数
returns something, you don't need this return key if your
会返回一个 Double 的值，所以你甚至都不需要使用 return
whole is just an expression like this return key word.
如果所有的代码只有一个返回语句
You don't need that key word because it knows this is
那就不需要 return 这个关键字
going to return something so
因为程序知道这里，你要返回什么东西
this is just an expression it's going to return it.
这样只需要输入一个表达式就可以了，编译器知道这个表达式的值就是你想返回的值
But it's even better than that because a swift does
而 Swift 还有一个更棒的功能是
not force you to name these two arguments.
Swift 不强制要求你给这两个参数命名
If you don‘t name them it will use the names $0.
如果不命名的参数的话，程序自动给参数起名为 $0
$1, and
和 $1
if you have more arguments, dollar 2, dollar 3, dollar 4.
如果你有更多的参数，将会命名为 $2，$3，$4...
So you don't even need this.
所以，函数名字也不要了
Okay?
明白了吗？
So this is a function right here.
所以这里的意思是，这是一个函数
It takes two doubles, dollar 0 and dollar 1, and
这个函数有两个 Double 类型参数，名称是 $0 和 $1
returns a double.
返回一个 Double 类型的值
Now Swift knows that they're doubles because it knows that
Swift 编译器知道它们是 Double 类型
you're passing them to perform an operation.
因为你将它们传递给 performOperation
If you were passing this to some other, a function that
如果把它们传递给其他的函数
took different kind of function as an argument, then,
这些函数有不一样的参数类型，那么
you know, these types might be different but in this case it
$0 和 $1 的类型可能和上面不同
knows that's what it is and it knows that it returns once
但是在这里，Swift 知道它们是什么类型
it knows it's going to return what this calculation is.
也知道它们的计算结果是什么类型的
All right.
明白了吗？
Now one more cool syntactic thing you can do is if you
更酷的事情是
have a function like performOperation, and
如果你有一个 performOperation 这样的函数
it has an argument which is a function like operation here,
有个像 operation 这样的函数作为一个参数
if this argument is the last argument, okay, so
如果这个参数是最后一个参数
if I had other arguments before it, and
在它之前有别的参数
this was the argument, then you can move the function.
这是传入的参数，那么你就可以把这个函数
Outside the parentheses, so other arguments,
移动到括号外，至于其他的参数
if there were other arguments before, they would go in here.
如果有的话，仍旧放在括号内
But this last argument,
但是最后的参数除外，可以放在括号之后
which is this operation, gets to go outside the parentheses.
也就是这个 operation，可以放在括号外
And if there are no other arguments, if this is
如果除了最后一个参数以外，没有其他的参数
the only argument, you can actually get rid of that.
简单的说，只有一个参数时，你可以把括号也去掉
Okay.
明白了吗？
So, we're cutting down to incredibly concise
因此，我们把我们乘法的代码变得相当简洁
language here and we can do this exact same deal,
我们再对其他的运算做同样的事情
of course with these other form operations.
复制粘贴这个代码
We just need to change the.
只需要改一下算数运算符
Nothing here.
这里不需要改
This one, we be a little careful with the order of
除法需要注意的是参数的顺序
operations here, we wanna do this because we
我们想把这两个参数的位置颠倒一下
click the thing that we're dividing by on the stack last.
是因为我们希望，除数是栈中的最后一个元素
And that's the first thing that comes off the stack.
而除数是栈中最先弹出的元素
And same thing here actually,
同样，这里也要注意减法的参数顺序
the subtraction minus dollar here.
$1 - $0
Okay, so, this is our entire operate, and
好了，这就是我们的全部的运算操作
you can see that it's incredibly concise.
你可以看到，与之前相比，这相当的简洁
Very readable.
同时也有很高的可读性
Times is clearly doing this function.
一眼看上去就知道这里是在做乘法
And very extensible.
同时，这样做保证了良好的可扩展性
If you wanna add more functions,
如果你需要添加更多的操作
we just one liners here,
只需要这里添加一行代码
but more these [COUGH] binary functions that have two So,
但在这里我们就只有这么多二元运算
let's go ahead and make sure these are all working.
让我们运行一下，以确保我们应用没有问题
All right.
好的
So, 6 enter 5 times, that's 30, that's good.
输入 6，enter，5，乘法，结果是 30
How about 47 plus 77, excellent.
再来，输入 47，加法，结果是 77，不错
How about 2 divide.
再输入 2，除法
38.5.
结果是 38.5
[INAUDIBLE] number there.
控制台也输出同样的结果
Working, you can see the stack doing all the right things.
一切都很好，控制台的输出也没有问题
Okay? Make sense?
没问题吧？
Now, I'm going to do one more thing, here.
现在，我还需要做一个事情
Which is to add another operation,
就是添加另外的一个运算操作
this is going to be a slightly different operation.
它完成一个稍有不同的操作
So, I'm going to copy and
这里，我复制一个运算符的按钮
paste these operation buttons here.
然后粘贴到这里
Again, I'm going to make sure they are lined up really
确保对齐
nice with as many of these blue lines as I can get.
我使用这些蓝色的线来确保对齐
I'm actually going to leave these buttons here.
我打算把按钮放在这个位置
Because you're going to need them for your homework.
因为你们等下做课后作业的时候会需要用到
But we gonna change this button right down here to be
我们将会让这个按钮
a different operator.
完成成为一个不同的运算
Which is going to be, square root.
它将是一个平方根运算符
Which is right here, square root operator.
就在这里，一个平方根
All right?
有什么问题吗？
And, so, I'm going to go back her to do square root, and
然后我回到这里的代码，添加一个平方根运算
it's just another case, right.
只需要再添加一个 case 就可以搞定了
Case square root.
case "√"
And, maybe I should just be able to use the same
也许这里我应该直接拷贝同样的代码
mechanism, right?
对吧？
Let's see if that works.
让我们看看，这样能不能行
Place that in there.
把它们放在这
And instead of this bracket here, let's use the built in
把花括号里的内容删掉，用一个
function in Swift to do square root called sqrt.
Swift 里内置的平方根运算函数，叫做 sqrt
And a dollar there.
还有一个 $0
Looks good.
看起来不错
And then we're ready to go.
好的，我们准备运行我们的应用
Let's just work, call it, what's going on here.
稍等，这里好像有什么问题
They have some sort of error, what's the problem.
好像是某种错误，是什么问题呢？
I don't understand.
我也不清楚
Let's take a look at this.
我们来看一看
Now this error is a little hard to understand but
这里的错误有点难理解，不过
basically what it's saying is that you're calling
大概意思是说，你使用的这个
performOperation here with an argument which is a function,
performOperatin 是个函数，它接受一个函数作为一个参数
it only takes on argument.
但是这个函数只有一个参数，正常的应该是有两个参数
Goes Swift looks here and
Swift 编译器检查了一个闭包
it's used that it's only using a dollar zero so
发现这个函数参数只使用了一个参数 $0
this is a one argument function this whole
也就是说这个函数只有一个参数
curly brace thing is a function that is one argument.
大括号里只有一个参数
Well four operation takes a function that
上面的四个运算调用的这个 performOperation 函数
has two arguments.
有两个参数
So that's a mismatch that doesn't work.
所以参数个数不匹配，导致了这个错误
So how can we fix this.
那么我们来修复这个错误
Well actually believe it or not we can just make a copy of
不管你相不相信，我们直接复制这个函数体
form operation of another method, same name.
相同的函数名字
This one we are gonna have different arguments.
但是这个函数与原来的函数有不同的参数个数
It's gonna have a, an argument which is
将只有一个参数
a function that only takes one double and returns a double.
只有一个 Double 参数，返回一个 Double 的值
And then inside here,
然后在函数体的内部
obviously we don't need topull two things off the stack,
显然我们不需要弹出两个元素
just one.
只弹出一个就行了
And obviously we only need to
同样，我们只需要确保
check to make sure there is one thing on the stack.
栈中至少存在一个元素
And look, all error warnings gone, okay?
现在看一看，所有的错误都消失了，对吧？
So it automatically figured out that this
所以，它自动搞清楚
performer operation must be this one,
他必须匹配哪个 performOperation 的函数
because this is a function that only has one argument.
因为这里只有一个参数 $0
And so it matched it up with this version of it.
所以它匹配了只有一个参数的函数的版本
So in Swift, you can have functions with the same name.
所以在 Swift 中，我们让函数有相同名字
As long as they have different arguments.
只要他们有不同的参数就可以了
And that Swift will
Swift 的编译器将会
automatically pick the right one, if it can.
自动选择正确的一个
There are sometimes when it's just like,
某些时候这就好比
I can't really tell which one you mean.
你不告诉它你到底想要的是哪个
And it will certainly complain, in that case.
在这种情况下，它当然会发牢骚了（报错）
But most of the type it's gonna be on [INAUDIBLE] from
但是，大部分情况
the types involved, what's going on.
它会通过参数类型判断到底使用哪个函数
So, just gonna run this one again real quick.
让我们运行一次这个程序
[INAUDIBLE] 36 square root.
输入 36，平方根
Looks like it's working,9 times square root.
答案正确，再输入 9，乘法，平方根
Excellent.
很好
Okay.
明白了吗？
All right. So,
我们继续
the last thing I'm going to do here is work on
我们要做的最后一件事
the layout of these buttons.
就是设置这些按钮的布局
So that's all I'm gonna do for the code.
我用代码写的就是这么多
You can see that we really didn't have to
你可以看到，我们实际上
write that much code.
并没有写太多代码
To make this work and
来让这个应用运行起来
we got to do a lot of stuff in our UI here.
我们而是在 UI 上做了很多事
So, let's go ahead and make it so these buttons spread out.
让我们继续，把这些按钮位置重新摆放
Cuz right now you see all this space is wasted right here.
因为你现在可以看到，我们浪费了很多空间
And on an iPhone in portrait mode.
如果 iPhone 在竖屏的时候
Whole bottom space is wasted.
我们下面的空间都浪费了
And an iPhone on landscape mode,
如果 iPhone 在横屏状态
this whole size can be wasted.
这块区域被浪费了
So I really want these buttons much bigger, and
所以我很想把这些按钮弄得大一些
stretching out.
拉伸开
Now, when you do something like that, you have to think
现在，如果你想做类似这样的事情，你需要认真
a little bit of kind of what your strategy is gonna be.
思考一下到底应该怎么做比较合适
You can't just kinda root four start, you know,
而不是急匆匆就开始随便就开始
control drag it between things.
用鼠标随便拖动这些按钮之类的
And trying to set up the horizontal spacing,
或是试着设置水平间距
and maybe line up the, make the equal width and height.
或是对齐这些线，设置相同的宽度和高度
Oh my gosh, you'd be control dragging all day long,
要是这么做你肯定得用鼠标拖一整天
by doing that.
So I'm not going to use control drag to do this.
所以我不会使用鼠标拖动来做这些事
I'm going to use these buttons down here which will kind of
我们将使用下面的这些按钮来布局
bulk out a layout buttons.
这些按钮称之为布局按钮
Let's go ahead and use the whole screen here.
我们先把这个界面扩大到全屏
Document outline.
把左边栏关掉
So what is going to be my strategy?
那么，我的策略是什么呢?
Well, my strategy is I'm going to make a perfect grid here.
我的策略就是在这做一个完美的网格
So, I almost have one, except for there's one missing here.
目前已经差不多了，不过左下角还缺一个按钮
So I'm actually going to take a button, copy and paste it.
所以我要复制一个按钮，然后粘贴在左下角的这个位置
Okay, just kind of be a dummy button here actually.
把这个当做一个占位按钮就行了
With no title.
不用添加任何标题
I'm going to right click on it also because I don't want it
然后右键单击这个按钮，因为我不想让它
sending appendage or anything else, So
和 controller 里的任何 Action 或者属性关联
its not going to send any messages.
现在，它就不会发送任何消息了
But it's just a dummy, so I'm kind of using.
现在我得费点
A little bit of brains over brawn here to do
脑筋来思考下这里的布局
this perfect grid.
这个完美的网格布局
Now if I have this perfect grid, then if I had a rule
现在我已经有了这个网格，接下来我需要一些规则
where all these buttons had to be the same size, and they all
例如，这些按钮需要相同的大小尺寸
had the same spacing between their neighbors, not just.
所有的按钮都要和他相邻的按钮
Between each other but the same spacing to this edge and
有相同的间距，还要和这个边界
the same spacing to this top edge.
或者顶部有相同的间距
Okay, if I had a rule like that then they would get
如果我有这么一个规则，那么
big and of course the spacing is facing from this edge
我们的按钮自然就会稀疏并且
to edge and this edge to this edge.
与四边有相同的间距
If it was all the exactly the same, which I'll make it be
如果这些按钮都有相同的规则
whatever this is, whatever the dash for the lines gave me.
那么无论这个按钮是什么
If that was the same then they would all have to spread out.
如果是规则一样的话，他们将都延伸开来
Okay, they'd get bigger but
好的，按钮之间会变的更稀疏，但是
they'd all stay the same size because I'm going to
我希望他们的尺寸都保持现在的大小，因为
make a rule that they have to be the same size.
我将制定一个规则来使他们保持大小
But they would move out to this edge so
但是这些按钮将移到这边
that this nearest neighbor would be the same, you know,
并且最近的元素保持相同的距离
this distance would be the same as this distance.
例如这个按钮到右边的间距将和它到它左侧按钮的间距是一样
So that's my strategy, I'm going to try to do that.
这就是我的想法，我们尝试一下
Now to make that work,
现在就开始
all these buttons need to know who their nearest neighbor is.
所有这些按钮需要知道他们的最近的元素是谁
Well, these all know their nearest neighbor here,
好，这些都知道他们的最近的元素
the other buttons, because I made sure I used dashed
也就是其他按钮的，因为当我拖拽它们时
blue lines when I dragged them in there.
我确保使用的蓝色虚线来对齐它们
So, that's what kind of
这也是某种
teaches them their nearest neighbor.
确定它们最近的元素的一种方式
And I'm also going to make sure that the entire grid
接下来，我要确保整个网格
knows that the left edge and
知道它的左边界
just under the label there, our nearest neighbor.
并且，知道它就位于这个标签的下面
So now it knows on the top,
现在，它知道
the nearest neighbor is the label, and
离它最近的顶部元素是这个标签，并且
on the left is this edge.
离它最近的左边元素是这个边界
And it's going to pick this edge as
我们要做的就是让这些按钮知道，右侧的边界是离他们最近的右侧元素
the nearest neighbor for these buttons and the bottom edge,
底部的边界是离他们最近的底部元素
cuz that's all there is and
因为这儿没有其他的东西
nothing else out here that's gonna become,
可以成为这些按钮的最近的元素
that's the only neighbor there is, it's gonna pick those.
它们只能选择这两个边界
So now that I've used my dash for
那么，现在我已经使用这些虚线
the lines it makes this all quite easy.
这将变的很容易
Now, if you don't use the dash for the lines, or
如果你不使用这些虚线
if you make some mistakes then it's not going to work.
或者你搞错了什么的话，它就不会有效的
This strategy won't work and I've made doing this part of
我做的这部分演示
this demonstration be extra credit.
是额外的
And so if you can't get it, don't worry about it too much,
因此，如果你不能做到或者不明白的话，也不必太担心
just keep all your buttons in the upper left corner here
只需保持你所有的按钮在左上角
and that's fine.
这就好了
But if you want to give this a try, the key is to
但是如果你想尝试一下我所做的
use the dash lines to make the perfect grid.
重点是使用虚线，来确保整个按钮网格是对齐的
Make sure that you set the nearest neighbors here by
同时通过拖拽整个网格确保你将左侧边界和这个标签
dragging the whole grid to make blue lines appear on the sides.
设置为离这些按钮最近的上部元素和左侧元素
And then, we are going to set these rules in bulk and
然后，我们来设置这些规则
we do that with these buttons down here.
我们可以用下面的这些按钮
So there's this button right here the left most button and
在最左边的这个按钮
it let's you set things like lining up leading edges or
它可以设置左边对齐
the tops or the centers.
上边对齐或者居中
And you could imagine there might be a way to do this by
也许你能想到，利用这些，可以实现我们想要的布局
doing that but I am not going to use that strategy.
但是我们在这里不会这么做
My strategy is just make them the same size and
我的方法就是让它们的大小一样
make the space in between them, be the same.
并且它们之间的间距也一样
But, I bet there's probably a way to do it by
但是，我相信，也许通过中点的方式
lining up their centers, or something like that, too.
或者类似的方式也可以做到一样的效果
So I'm not going to use this one.
因此，我这里不打算使用个按钮
The next one over,
下一个按钮
right here, is the one that has the things I want.
这里就有我想要的东西
And so you can see that it'll ask you to
正如你所看见的，它会让你选择
make all the buttons equal widths and heights.
是否让所有按钮的宽度相等、高度相等
Okay, not width and
没有勾选的这两个选项（Width，Height）
height, that fixes them at a certain width and
是用来将它们修改成某个特定的宽度和高度的
height, this means that there,they can be any width and
但是这里的意思是，对于所有的这些按钮，宽度和高度可以是任意的值
height they want, but they all have to be the same width and
但是他们必须拥有相同的宽度和相同的高度
height all these buttons.
Of course I had these all selected by the way, if you
当然，我把这些按钮都选中了
don't have them selected it doesn't make any sense.
如果你没选中那就不会应用这些规则
And then up here, you can see there is spacing to
然后在这里，你可以看到这是一个 Spacing to
nearest neighbor, so this is where I am going to set
nearest neighbor 的面板，我们把这些
that spacing between all these, to be the same.
按钮之间的间距设为一样
And you can see that it's put eight here.
正如你所看到的，这里设置为 8
That's because when I did the dash lines
这是因为当我使用虚线对齐元素时
to the top eight seems to be kind of a standard number of
标准的间距就是 8 个像素点
points between elements.
These are all multiple because some of these buttons,
这里显示所有的左间距为 Multiple，那是因为这些按钮中
their nearest neighbor is way over here and it's huge.
有些最近的元素是右边界，这是一个巨大的数值
All right.
明白了吗？
The bottom or their right.
最近的下边元素和右边元素的数值不一样导致 Multiple
But all these buttons,the thing on top,
所有这些按钮，最近的上部元素
whether it's another button or whether it's this label,
无论是另一个按钮或者是这个标签
all of them happen to be this eight points right here.
他们的间距都是 8 个像素点
So I want all of these to be eight.
我想让这些都设置为 8 个像素点
So I'm just going to turn this bar on right here, which says,
在这里我们打开这一栏
yes please enforce, and make the rule that all of
“ 请确保这些所有
these are 8 points from their nearest neighbor to the top.
按钮的到距离它顶部最近元素距离为 8 个像素点 ”
And also, 8 to the left,8 to the right, and
同样，左边间距为 8 个像素点，右边间距为 8 个像素点
8 to the bottom.
底部间距也为 8 个像素点
Really wanna make sure these beams are on,
确保这里是打开的
if these beams are off,even if there's a number here,
如果他是关闭的，即使这里有数字
then it's not gonna add this rule.
也不会添加规则的
So we wanted to add this rule.·
我们想要添加这些规则
So this adds up to
87 different rules.
所以总共有 87 个不同的规则
All these equal widths and
所有相同宽度，相同高度
heights and all these So if you don't have 87 in here,
以及这些，如果你的规则的数目不是 87
if it says a hundred and something,
假如是 100 或者其它，
probably you don't have everything lined up right.
那么很可能你没有将所有东西正确对齐起来
It only takes 87 constraints to express all these rules.
只需要 87 个规则就可以表示我们想要的网格布局
All right.
明白了吗？
Now, when I click this Add 87 Constraints it's
现在，如果我按下 “Add 87 Constraints”
going to add these rules to all these buttons, and
就会在这些按钮上添加这些规则
watch what happens.
看看会发生什么
So, I get all kinds of,
嗯，我得到了很多的线
first these blue lines are showing me the rules.
首先这些蓝色的线表示规则
'Kay? A lot them are saying here
许多蓝色的线代表这里
that things are equal widths and heights.
的按钮都是相同长度和宽度的
So these are what equals rules means.
这就是 equals 规则的意思
But there's also tiny little I beams right up here.
这里还有一些小的 I 形状的线
That are showing this basing to nearest neighbor, and
I 行的线表示以最近的物体为基准
also like there's a yellow, yellow here.
这里还有一些黄色的线
This yellow, remember, means yeah,
记住，这些黄色的线代表
there's constraints on these, but they're not actually where
这里虽然有一些规则，但是这些东西的位置本不应该
they're supposed to be based on those rules.
放置在这里，也就是说，目前的位置和预想的位置有偏差
So we really want to move them all to be in their
我们很需要将这些按钮，按照这些规则
proper spaces based on these rules.
移动到合适的地方
That's what these dashed yellow lines mean.
这就是这些黄色的线的意思
So we can do the same thing to do that,
我们可以像按刚开始
that we did at the beginning with the label on the top
处理顶部的标签那样
which is go to our document outline here,
点击左下角的 document outline 菜单
in the lower left corner.
Okay these are document outline when we last saw it,
这些是 UI 文档的缩略图，上一次我们查看时
it only had this one label in there.
只有这一个标签在这里
Now we got all these buttons added.
现在把所有的按钮都添加上来了
And you can see they're all selected.
而且你看到这些按钮都处于选中状态
All selected here as well.
在 Storyboard 中也处于全部选中的状态
And, we've got this little yellow thing up here.
这上面有一个黄色的小箭头
Now, if this is red, okay, if you do all this and
如果这里是红色箭头，如果你做了之前的这些操作
this is red, well that means that you've got not just
并且是红色箭头，那就意味着你所添加的
warnings that your constraints aren't in the right place, but
规则不仅是警告，警告你目标的位置和预期的规则不同
you've got errors, usually conflicting constraints,
而且有错误，错误通常是由规则之间的冲突所引起
where you've asked auto layout to
当你让自动布局强制
enforce two rules that conflict with each other.
实施两种相互冲突的规则时
So if you get to that red, this is not going to work.
所以如果箭头是红色，这些规则就不会正常工作
So, you'll want to start over, and
这是，你可能想重新再设置一遍
I'll show you in a minute how you can start over if things,
我稍后为大家展示怎么再重新开始
or not going your way, but if it's yellow that just means
如果和你想的不同，黄色箭头
things were in the wrong place.
仅代表有些东西在错误的位置
So no problem, we click the yellow.
很简单，点击黄色箭头
Here's all the things that were in the wrong place.
这里是在错误位置的东西
This is all the buttons,
这是所有的按钮
you can see they highlight as I mouse over them.
你可以看到当鼠标移到按钮上时，对应的按钮高亮
And you can really pick on any one of them to fix this
你可以任意选一个来修改
because there's a nice little switch here called apply to
因为这里有一个很方便的复选框，它代表
all views and containers.
将修改应用到所有视图（views）和容器（containers）
You don't have to click on each one and
你就不必每一个都点击
have it to frame update to the proper thing.
使它的 frame 更新到合适的大小
You can just click quite obvious in container and it's
你可以很容易的选中复选框
going to move the frame of all the buttons to fix the fact
这样就会移动所有按钮的 frame，修改
that they're in the wrong place based on their rules.
那些处于错误位置的
So let's try that.
让我们试试看
I'm gonna hit this button here, Fix Misplacement.
我要点击这个按钮，“Fix Misplacement”
And it moved them all.
所有的按钮都移动了
There's no more yellow.
没有黄色的警告了
There's no auto layout issues.
没有自动布局的问题了
Okay. All looks good here.
看起来不错
We can close our document outline.
可以关闭 document outline 视图了
We zoom out, we can see, wow, it spread them all out.
将视图缩小，可以看到按钮充满了整个视图
Okay? Because,
maybe it's obeying those rules I gave it.
因为他们都遵守我定下的规则
Okay?
So let's now run this on some devices here and
现在，试试在不同的设备上运行
see what this looks like.
看看结果会怎样
So turn off on an iPhone 6, which is a pretty tall device.
在 特别长的 iPhone 6 上
It's made, you know, kind of tall and thin.
iPhone 6 做的既长又窄
So if this still works fine enter.
一切正常
69874 times 5 divide maybe square root something like
输入 5，enter，69874，乘法，5，除以，开平方根
that, it all seems to be working.
看起来运行正常
Now, not only is it working here in this portrait mode,
自动布局不但在 iPhone 竖屏时工作正常
tall and thin.
既长又窄的情况
But if we go over here to this we can rotate the device.
如果我们从这里旋转设备
Okay, so I'm going to rotate left and
我要通过 ⌘ + 左，右键来
right and use the command keys to do this.
旋转设备
And we rotate it right and you see it
设备向右转可以看到
may the buttons spread out to this new location and
按钮均匀分布到新的位置
we can rotate back using the command keys here.
可以用 ⌘ + 左，右键将设备转回来
And it looks good in either orientation.
可以看到，在两个方向上看起来都不错
And in fact, it can look good on other devices as well.
实际上，在其他设备上同样看起来很棒
So let's go over here and
点击这里
instead of doing iPhone 6, let's try it on an iPhone 4S.
这次不用 iPhone 6，试一下 iPhone 4S 上的效果
Okay so,
gonna switch the simulation here, let's run that.
切换模拟器，运行
Now the iPhone 4s, you can see is a little shorter,
现在是 iPhone 4S，它看起来短一点
it's not quite as tall.
并没有那么长
A little lower resolution, obviously.
很明显，分辨率也有些低
But it relayed out the buttons to look good in that case too.
但是在这种情况下也将按钮的位置摆放的很棒
9 times 9, divided by 8, square root, et cetera.
输入 9，enter，9，乘法，8，除法，开平方等等
And same thing here we can rotate and
同样我们可以旋转
look at this one as well.
这样看起来也不错
Okay.
明白了吗？
All righty.
好的
So the last thing I just want to talk about briefly is if
最后我想简单说下
you try this extra credit and it doesn't work for you.
你尝试得到额外加分，这是行不通的
Get all messed up, you can kind of start over by clicking
打乱所有限制，你可以通过点击
on this and using the third button over here on the right.
这个位置并使用右边第三个按钮重新开始
And this allows you to reset your constraints and
这里允许你重置你的约束，
you can see the top section here is the selected views.
你能看到上面的部分是被选中的视图
I don't have any selected here so
我这里没有任何选中的视图，因此
this wouldn't do anything right now.
现在这里不能做任何操作
But the bottom is all views in container and
但是下面的部分是容器内的所有视图
I kinda recommend going down here to all views
我推荐到下面所有视图
container and clearing the constraints entirely.
容器内并清除所有约束
Reset to suggested constraints and try and
重置到建议的约束条件,
make some sense of your dashed lines but if it's not working,
但如果不工作，
you're probably, you're dashed lines are off anyway.
你很可能，
So you can just go here and
因此你仅仅需要到这里
Clear Constraints, that'll clear them all.
清除所有约束条件，这将清除所有限制
Now that's gonna clear not just your buttons but
现在不仅仅需要清除你的按钮，而且
also it's gonna clear your labels.
需要清除你的标签
So you'll have to reposition your label with blue lines and
所以你必须使用蓝色线条重新放置你的标签并且
use control drag to say your top space, and, and
拖拽来确定你上部的空间
all that stuff, you know?
所有东西，了解？
If your buttons are really huge, they got really huge,
如果你所有按钮确认很大，他们会变得很大，
but they're not in the right place, you can actually change
但是他们不能在正确的位置，你可以根据实际情况在工具窗口中调整
the size of all your buttons in the utilities window.
你的按钮的大小
You can go to the size inspector right here,
有可以到尺寸查看器这里
that's this one, you can actually type in the width and
这个位置你可以输入所期望按钮的实际宽度和
the height you want the buttons to be, make them
高度，确保他们
smaller again, which, you know, maybe 64 by 64.
再次变小，就像你所知道的那样 可能是 64 x 64
That might make them easier to re-drag them into position so
这可以是他们变得容易再次拖拽到适当位置，
the blue lines are working.
蓝色线条正常工作
And don't forget the very important blue line dragging,
不要忘记这个很重要的蓝色线条的拖拽，
which is you want to take the whole grid and drag it,
你想要拖拽挣个格栏，
so that it's sitting underneath your label.
以至于它在你标签下方
If you have problems dragging the whole grid underneath your
如果你拖拽你标签下面的整个格栏有问题，
label, sometimes it's a good idea, clear all
通常清除所有约束限制是个好的做法
your constraints, kind of move your buttons out of the way,
移动你的按钮到远处，
just kind of move them down to the bottom here and then
仅仅移动他们到底部，然后
just for your label, do reset to suggest your constraint.
对你的标签，做重置到建议的约束条件
This top one selected view
最上面那个被选中的视图，
Rest Suggestion Constraints cuz that will work for
重置建议的约束条件英文这将对你的标签起作用
the label if you move it into position as long as
你可以移动他倒适当位置只要
the buttons aren't too close and it thinks that, you know.
按钮们不要靠的太近
Those buttons are near neighbors or something.
这些按钮是进邻或者其他什么
And sometimes resetting it to suggest the constraints will
一些情况，重置到推荐约束
make it so that, that bottom edge of your UI label will
能做到，UI 标签下边缘是
be attainable when you drag your buttons into position.
可以达到的，当你拖拽一个按钮到一个位置
But again, not to
但是，不要
worry too much about this auto layout stuff.
太担心界面自动布局的内容
It's extra credit in assignment one.
这是作业一的额外加分
It's not going to be extra credit in assignment two,
到了作业二就不是额外加分了
so you're eventually going to have to do it.
最终你都要做这件事
I'm going to be giving a big lecture on this in a couple of
我将花好几个星期给你们好好讲一下
weeks, on auto layout.
自动布局
I've really just shown you just kind of what it can do,
我仅仅向你们展示了它的小小一角
I haven't really taught you how to do
我以前没有教你们如何设置
auto layout in particular.
自动布局
Auto layout is very important because we work in this
自动布局十分重要因为我们
square area and
在这个方框被做工作
we want our UIs to work on all kinds of different devices.
我想要我们的界面能再各种不同设备上正常工作
That's why we're starting off in the very
这也是我们用它
start with some experience with it.
作为入门的原因
All right.
好了
So that is it.
就这样
Now, later today, I'm gonna, in this lecture,
稍后，这次课中
I'm gonna give you a talk about this design paradigm
我将要给你讲关于设计模式
called model-view-controller, and we actually designed our
叫做 模型 - 视图 - 控制器，事实上我们设计的
calculator kind of poorly, because all of
计算器很差，因为这里的所有
this code here is really nothing to do with UI.
代码和界面没有任何关系
This is all calculator brain, calculator engine code.
这是所有计算器的核心，计算器的引擎代码
And this really wants to meet a different object and
这里需要接触一个不同的对象，
that's what MVC is all about.
这也就是 MVC
And so I'll give a little talk about MVC later today.
今天稍后我将讲关于 MVC 的内容
And then on Monday, we're going to fix our calculator
然后再周一，我们将要解决我们计算器的问题，
to obey MVC and be a proper citizen in the iOS world,
达到遵循 MVC 架构，并成为 iOS 世界里的一员，
where all apps need to obey model V controller paradigm.
在这里所有的程序都需要遵循 MVC 模式
>> So let's try and
understand for, I mean half of
来让我们尝试并理解，据你们说过半的人
you said that you already know MVC or you've seen it
知道 MVC 或者在其他
somewhere else so, this is going to be mostly review.
地方听过它，因此这里将是复习
But the other half of you, this will hopefully give you
另外一半人，这里将给你
an idea of what MVC is all about.
一个 MVC 相关的概念
So MVC is basically a mechanism where we divide up
MVC 是一个基本机制，用于分类
all the objects in our application into one of
程序中的所有对象到
these three camps.
三个营地中的任意一个
Okay?
了解？
So, the three camps.
三个营地 （或者叫三层）
On the left there you see the model.
在左边你看到的是模型
So, the model camp is gonna be all the objects that are what
模型层是那些对象的集合，这些对象是
your application does.
是程序的行为
So, for our calculator its, it calculates.
在我们计算器中，计算是模型
Okay, that's what it does.
那是计算器要做的
So, all the parts what we're doing perform operation, and
我们用于做执行操作的部分，和
all that stuff, that's all kind of calculator stuff.
相关材料，也就是计算器相关的内容
That should be in a calculator object somewhere else,
那些应属于计算器对象
it shouldn't be in our controller.
不应该在我们的控制器中
And then the second camp is the controller, the controller
第二个阵营叫做 controller ，controller
controls how the model is presented on screen.
控制模型是如何显示在屏幕上
And the view is the minions, the classes that
视图是 controller 要
the controller is going to use are kind of
用到的的附属类，有点类似于
like the the building blocks, the Lincoln Logs,
像积木，林肯积木，
I know maybe that's before all of your time.
我知道这也许是在你所有的时间。
But, you know, these things we're gong to do to build our
但是，这些事情是我们构建我们界面
UI, we're going to use in the view.
要做的事，我们在 view 中要用到它
So the stuff that's in the view is pretty generic, okay,
在 view 中的内容是相当通用的
generic UI elements.
的界面元素
The stuff in the controller is very specific to
在控制器中的内容是明确的，指出
how your UI works.
你的界面元素是如何工作的
And the stuff in the model is completely independent of
模型中的内容完全独立于
how your UI works.
界面如何工作的
Okay?
懂吗？
So doing MVC right is about knowing where things go but
因此正确的 MVC 不仅仅知道内容的存放位置而且
also about how to communicate between these three camps.
知道三层（camps）是如何通讯的
And so we can try and summarize how
我们来尝试总结，
the communication works between these camps, and
三层之间是如何通讯的，
I've used road markings, you see the double yellow line and
我使用路面标线做讲解，你看到的黄色双线和
then the dashed white line.
白色虚线
So that's like you're driving in your car.
就像你驾驶你的汽车
Try to use them as an image for how this communication
尝试用做以道路标线想象是如何通信的
happens, where it's allowed, where it's not allowed.
哪里是允许通信的，哪里是不被允许的
So let's talk about the Controller talking to
这样，我们描述控制器是如何与
the Model.
模型
Going from that side of the road over to the Model side is
从控制器这侧到模型 (Model) 这侧是
a dashed white line, in other words,
白色虚线，换句话说，
you can head right across there.
你可以轧过虚线到另一侧
You probably want to look before you go, but
你可能需要在你过对面之前观察一下，但是
you can go right across, okay?
你可以正常穿越，对吗？
The controller has to know everything about the model,
控制器必须了解 Model 的一切行为，
and it has to have complete ability to talk to
而且必须完全有能力和
the model, use its public API as much as it wants
模型（Model）通信，根据控制器需要，使用模型的开放 API
because the controller's job is to present the model to
因为控制器的职责就是展示模型（Model）给
the user using its view as its minions.
用户，其视图作为它的对象
So it has to have this access.
因此你必须有该权限
That full, unrestricted access the controller has talking to
控制器拥有的完全访问权限可以与
the model.
模型通信
This is a one way arrow.
这是个单向箭头
Control, or
控制器
one way arrow, from the controller to the model.
对模型的控制也是单向的
And similarly, from the controller to the view,
类似的，也可以从控制器到视图，
is also unlimited communication,
也是允许通信的
because the controller is responsible for
因为控制器负责通过自身对象
talking using it's own minions.
向视图发送指令
The view is, the controller's new meaning is
视图是控制器设计
to lay out the user interface and all that stuff.
用户界面的新方式
So, the controller can do anything it wants.
因此，控制器可以做任何它想做的事
I put that little green word, outlet,
我放置了一个绿色小字 Outlet 在上面，
up there because when we have a property of a controller
因为当我们有一个控制器的属性，
that points into the view, we call it an outlet, okay?
该属性指向视图，我们称它为 Outlet，懂吗？
And you're gonna see that in the demo on Wednesday.
我们周三的演示中将要看到它
I'm gonna say, oh let's create an outlet from our controller
我想说的，让我们创建一个 outlet， 从我们的控制器
to our view so
到我们的视图
our controller can talk to it's view, all right?
这样，我们控制器可以发送指令到对应视图 对吧？
What about this communication?
这是如何通信的呢？
Model to view?
可以从 Model 到视图吗？
Never.
不可能！
And why is that?
为什么会这样呢？
100% obvious, the model is completely UI independent.
很明显，Model 是完全独立于 UI 的
So, there's absolutely no way it could talk to
因此，Model 没有任何办法向
a viewer object or anyone in that camp.
视图对象发送指令，也不能和视图层的任何对象通讯
Because the view objects are fundamentally UI objects.
因为视图对象是基本的 UI 对象
They're kind of generic, but
他们是某种程度上是通用的，但是
they're still fundamentally UI objects.
他们也是基本的 UI 对象
Similarly, since the view objects are kind of generic,
同样地，既然视图对象是通用的对象，
they can't be talking to any specific model.
他们就不能和任何特定的 Model 对象通讯
They need a controller to interpret a model
他们需要用一个控制器来传到信息
for them, okay?
懂吗？
So there's never any communication this way.
因此这里没有任何通信
That's why it's a double yellow line.
这也是这里使用黄色双线的原因
That's why these lines are red.
这是这些线是红色的原因
That's why there's fire, okay?
这也是这里用火标注的原因 明白？
Never go across that line, Never.
永远不要跨越这条线， 绝不！
What about the view talking back to the controller?
那视图怎么样向控制器发送指令呢？
You got these generic view objects, like buttons.
你得到这些通用的视图对象，例如按钮
Can they talk to the controller?
他们能与控制器通信吗？
Well, yes, they can.
对，当然可以
But, they have to be careful because the view objects
但是你必须小心，因为视图对象
are generic.
是通用的
So they can't really know much about the controller.
这样，他们不能真正的了解控制器
So, they can only communicate back to the controller
因此他们只能用盲目的方式和控制器通信，
in a blind way where they don't know the class of
视图并不知道他们所通信的类
the thing they're talking to, and in a structured way.
在什么位置，并用一种结构化的方式和控制器通信
A way where we all agree we're gonna communicate this way
这是一种大家都认同的，视图和控制器通信的
between the view and the controller.
方式
So, whats an example of a structured way?
那，有没有是结构化的方式例子？
Well one is called target action.
其中一个方式叫做 Target 操作
So, the controller basically drops a target on itself, and
一般控制器本身写一个 target
then it hands out an action, which is like an arrow,
然后分给出一个操作方法，想一个箭头
to the view and says to the view,
指向视图，并和视图通信
okay, when you do what you do, like you're a button and
当你想做了一个操作，比如你是一个按钮，
someone touches you or your a slider and
别人点击了你，或者你是个拖动条
someone moves you, send me that action.
别人移动了你，给向我发送那个操作
Okay?
懂吗？
So, in this way, the generic button or
这样，用这种方式，通用的按钮或者
slider is communicating back to the controller.
拖动条就可以反过来和控制器通信
It has no idea that it's a card game controller or
它不知道这是一个纸牌游戏控制器还是
a space game controller.
一个空间游戏控制器
It doesn't know what kind of controller it is.
它并不知道它是什么类型的控制器
All it knows is that when something happens in itself,
它所知道的只是某一个事件何时在它身上发生
boom, it sends a message to the target.
它发送一个消息给 target
So that's a blind, simple, structured way for
这样就是一个盲目的，简单的，结构化的方式来做
the view to communicate with the controller.
到视图和控制器之间的通信
Okay?
明白吗？
But what about more complicated ways?
那什么是更复杂的通信方式呢？
Sometimes the view, things are happening in the view
有时，发生在视图上的事件
that are somewhat complicated, and
是比较复杂的，
the controller needs to be informed of what's going on,
控制器需要知道正在发生的事是什么，
synchronizing what's happening.
同步正在发生的事件
And one way to think about this is these words I
理解这个的一种方法是我放着
put up here, will, should and did.
will, should 和 did 这些单词，
When the view is kind of like,
当某种视图
let's say I am in the scroll view and
就比如说是在一个 scroll 视图中，
I am scrolling around, and I want to let the controller
我正在到处滚动，并且我想要让控制器
somebody know that the user just did scroll.
知道用户刚刚做了滚动操作
Okay? Or
懂吗？或者
the user puts down the touch and is about to scroll, I want
用户按住屏幕，将要滑动，我想让
to let the controller know the user will be scrolling, okay?
控制器知道用户将要执行滑动操作 懂吗？
Or, the user puts the touch down and
或者用户按住屏幕
the scroll viewer wants to know,
scroll viewer 需要知道
should I allow the user to scroll here, is that allowed?
是否允许用户这里执行滚动操作？
All those things, the scroll view itself might not
这里所有的事情，scroll 视图本身或许没有
have enough logic to know the answer to those questions.
足够的逻辑知道那些问题的答案
So what it does is, it delegates the authority to
那它做的事情是，它代理给
answer those questions to some other object.
其他对象来回答那些问题
Now, it doesn't know the class of that object.
现在，它并不知道那个对象的类是什么
All it knows is that other object can
他知道只是另一个对象可以
answer these questions, will, should, did, this, that, or
回答这些问题，will, should, did, this, that, 或者
the other thing like, should allow scrolling.
其他事情，像是否允许滑动
Did scroll to point.
滑动到一个点
Things like that.
就像那样
So those are the kind of
这些是这样一类
methods you are going to see in these delicate protocols.
方法，你将要在那些代理协议中看到他们
Now, I know this here is 1, 6 a and b,
现在，我知道这里是 1，6，a 和 b
do not teach protocols.
没有教过协议，
How many people know what
多少人知道
the word protocol means an
object during a programming?
协议在编程中代表什么对象？
I can see very few of you.
很少能做到
So, I will be teaching that.
这里我将要讲它
A protocol is just a blind way to talk to another object.
协议仅仅是 blind 和其他对象通信的方式
When I teach it,
我讲了它以后，
you're gonna be like oh, yeah, I know what that is.
你将会明白，这知道这就是它
So we can really call it protocol or whatever.
我们实际上叫它协议，或者不管什么了
But that's how we do delegation, okay,
但这是我们如何实现一个代理，
this blind communication.
盲目通信
Also another important thing is
另一个重要事情是
that views should not own the data that they're displaying.
视图不应该持有他们展示的数据
They should not own it.
他们不应该持有数据
In other words, it shouldn't be a property inside of them,
换句话说，数据不应该作为视图内部的属性，
where that's the truth of that data.
这就是数据。
And the easiest example for this is, all the songs in
最简单的例子就是，在
your iPod, on your iPhone or your iPad, right?
你 iPod,iPhone 或者 iPad 中的所有歌曲 对吗？
You might have 10,000 songs in there.
你可能有 10000 首歌曲
So, if you have some kind of generic list view in
假如你有一些通用的视图列表在你视图中，
your view, you can't transfer all 10,000 songs to its
你不能传递 10000 首歌到它的
instance variables, and
实例变量中，并
expect it to hold 10,000 songs so it can list through it.
期望它来持有 10000 首歌，来展示给你看
A, that would be inefficient, and
第一，这样做是很低效的，
B that information, those 10,000 songs belongs where?
第二，这 10000 首歌属于哪一层？
In the model.
在 Model 层
Okay, because your song database is a model.
OKay，因为你的音乐数据库是一个 Model
It has nothing to do with UI.
它和 UI 没有任何关系
It's just a list of songs and artists and albums and
视图仅仅是歌曲，艺术家，专辑和其他信息的一个列表
all that, it's in the model.
它在 Model 层
Some controller has to look at that database and
一些控制器必须查询数据并
tell a view how to display all those songs.
告诉一个视图如何展示这些歌曲
Okay?
懂吗？
So, we need that communication to happen here and the view is
这里，我们这里需要通信产生, 视图
displaying some sort of list, and you're touching down and
展示列表分类，并且当你按下屏幕，
you're flicking on the list and trying to see more songs,
你轻轻滑动列表，试图查看更多歌曲，
how does that communication happen?
这些通信如何发生的？
And the answer is, we have another special kind of
答案是我们 有另一种特殊的
delegate, which we call a data source.
代理，我们叫它数据源
Now the data source doesn't do the will did should.
数据源并不做 will, did, should 的事
It's gonna be asking questions like count,
它将回答类似，数量
like how many songs are there?
像这里有多少首歌？
And the controller looks in the model,
控制器查找 Model
10,000 response to the view.
把 10000 返回给视图
There's 10,000. The view
这是 10000, 视图
makes space internally for 10,000 things.
为 10000 歌开辟内部空间
It doesn't know what they are.
视图并不知道这些歌曲是什么
Moves the scroll bar indicator a little bit so
稍微移动滚动条
that you know where it is.
你便能知道它在哪里
And then you start scrolling, flipping through it, and
当你开始滚动，轻滑动它，
it starts sending the message to the controller,
它开始发送消息给控制器
give me the data at line 150 next 10 items.
返回 150 行后面的 10 条数据
You see what I mean?
你懂我意思吗？
And then you flick down some more.
然后你再往下轻轻滑动
Now it's saying 250, 10 more items.
现在显示 250， 另外 10 条数据
And so the control is going back to the model and
控制器再次与 Model 通信，并
saying give me more, give me more data.
要求得到更多的数据
And it's providing it to the view in this blind way.
控制器用这种 blind 方式提供数据给视图
So to see how the view is getting data from the model
来看一下视图如何从 Model 得到数据,
through the controller in this kind of blind structured way.
是通过控制器用这种 blind structured 方式实现的
Okay?
懂吗？
That makes sense to everybody?
每个人都明白吗？
So data source is just a kind of delegate,
数据源只是一种代理
it's a specific kind of delegate for getting data.
它是一种特殊类型的用于获取数据的代理
So you're gonna see that there are classes in iOS that have
因此你将在 iOS 中看到一些类，
a data source, and they usually also have a delegate.
他们有一个数据源，并且通常有一个代理
Most sophisticated classes in iOS have a delegate, the will,
大部分 iOS 高级类有代理，包括 will,
did, should, kind of things.
did, should, 等要做的事
Some of them have a data source,
其中一些有数据源，
it depends on whether they are showing a lot of data or not.
这取决于他们是否要显示大量数据
Now simple data, like if I had a view, if I invented a view
一些简单的数据，比如我给纸牌游戏
for my card game called Playing Card View and
创建了一个叫 Playing Card View 的视图
it just has a suit and a rank.
它仅有花色和点数两点属性
Okay, we're not going to do count data app for
我们不会为了花色和点数
just suit and rank.
进行计算
We are going to set those properties.
我们会把它们设置成属性
And so the view then would have that data set in it but
所以 view 里会有设置好的数据，但是
it wouldn't be owning it.
它不会拥有这些数据
Right? The model would still be
model 仍然会是花色和点数的
owning the suit and
拥有者
rank, the view is just getting that data to present it.
view 仅仅是为了显示而获取那些数据
'Kay. So simple data,
所以对于简单的数据，
we might transfer to the view but it's merely for
我们会把它传递到 view 里，但是
it to display it.
只是给 view 来显示
Okay.
This all adds up to the controller's job being to
所以 controller 的工作就是
interpret and format the model's data for the view.
给 view 解释并格式化这些 model 提供的数据
That's the controller's job.
这就是 controller 的工作
And when we do our demo,
在我们做 demo 的时候，
I'm going to be marking like, oh see I'm writing this code.
我会在写代码的时候提示大家，
This is to make the controller perform its job,
这段代码是为了让 controller 执行它的工作，
which is to take the model data and
也就是从 model 中取出数据然后
using its view minion to put it on screen.
送到 view 中去，然后显示到屏幕上
Okay? That's what
这就是
the controller does.
controller 做的事情
What about this communication?
那关于通信呢？
Can the model talk to the controller?
model 可以和 controller 通信吗？
Again, obviously that's verboten because model knows
同样的，显然是不可以 因为 model 对于 UI
nothing about UI, so
一无所知，所以
it couldn't possibly talk to a UI object like the controller.
它不可能同像 controller 一样的 UI 对象进行通信
But sometimes things change in the model, and
但是有些时候，model 中的数据变了，
the controller needs to know about it, okay?
controller 需要知道这个变化
Data changes, a database changes or
数据改变了，数据库改变了，或者
the model is some network database, and
model 是网络数据库，
somebody changes something on the network and it changes.
某人在网络上修改了数据，数据改变了
And the controller needs to find out.
controller 需要了解这些
So, how do we do that communication?
所以，我们怎样进行这种通信呢？
We do that using kind of a radio station model.
这可以通过一种电台的模型来理解
Okay?
So, the model, a radio station concept, the model will use
所以，model 是一种电台的概念，
this concept to essentially broadcast information to
model 将会利用这一概念，把信息广播给
anyone who's interested.
感兴趣的任何人
Okay?
And the mechanisms for doing this in iOS are called
在 iOS 中为了解决这种问题而使用的技术我们叫做
Notification and Key Value Observing, KVO we call it.
Notification 和 KVO
And so, the model can just say, oh, anytime
所以，model 可以这样，
something changes in my model I'm just gonna broadcast on
我当中的任何东西发生了变化，我会通过我的电台
my radio station, and then the controller simply tunes into
广播一下，随后，controller
that radio station, and he can find out things are changing.
会接收到来自电台的信息，它会发现数据在变化
And when he finds out something changes,
发现数据变化以后，
it's gonna communicate via its green arrow to the model and
它就会通过它的绿剪头同 model 进行通信，
say, okay, give me that data that changed.
给我那个改变过的数据
Right?
That make sense?
能听懂吗？
So, towards the end of the quarter we'll start seeing
所以在课程快要结束的时候，我们将会学习
a little how to do notification to find out, for
如何利用 notification 得知
example, if the data in a database changes.
例如数据库中的数据发生了改变
We'll get a notification, the UI can then, you know,
我们将会获取一个 notification，UI 的 controller
controller can then go talk to the model to get the info.
随后可以同 model 通信来获取信息
Okay?
Some people have asked,
有些人会问，
can a view tune into the radio station?
view 可以接收广播吗？
They probably could, but
它们也许可以，但是
you probably wouldn't want to do that.
你最好不要这样做
That would probably be a violation of MVC.
这可能违背了 MVC 的原则
All right.
So we do this.
我们这样做，
We have all this nice communication and
我们有这些很好的通信方式和
all these rules,
所有的这些规则
and we can imagine building something simple using this.
我们可以利用这些来制作一些小的应用
But what if we wanna build a big complicated app?
但是如果我们想要制作一个巨大复杂的应用呢？
An app that has multiple screens on our iPhone, or
一个在 iPhone 或 iPad 上运行，有多个屏幕，
an iPad, it's got three or
在屏幕上有三个或四个不同的区域，
four different areas on screen where things are happening.
都发生着事情
How do we do that?
我们该怎么做？
Well, we're essentially going to
我们会结合
combine multiple MVCs, okay?
多个 MVC
Because an MVC can use as part of its view, another MVC.
因为一个 MVC 可以将另一个 MVC 当做视图的一部分
Okay?
So an MVC, an entire MVC can be one of
所以一个完整的 MVC 可以被一个稍大些的
the minions of some bigger MVC.
MVC 当做仆从使用
'Kay?
And by doing that and cascading it down,
我们可以一层一层地这样堆叠，
we can build more and more complicated applications.
就可以制作出越来越复杂的应用
So, an example of this is, you might have your calendar app,
例如，你可能有一个日历应用，
and it's showing you the entire year.
它展示给你一整年的信息
And you click on a month, and now it shows you a month view.
随后你点击了一个月份，于是它展示给你月视图
Well, a month view looks a lot different than a year view.
月视图看起来和年视图就不太一样了
A month view just has all the days and maybe some circle
一个月视图只含有日期，也许在日期上
that tells you where you have an appointment on a day.
会有一些通知你在某天会有任务的圈圈
And then when you click on a day, and
随后，你点击了一天，然后你
now you get a day view, okay?
获得了一个日视图
And the day is showing you the hours and what all
日视图会显示小时信息和这天你的所有任务，
your appointments are, and you click on the Appointment now
随后你点击了任务，
you get an appointment view and it showing the detail of
你会获得任务视图，它会显示任务的细节，
where you're going and when it is et cetera, okay?
将要去哪，何时动身还有其它一些东西
Well, each of those views, year view, month view, the day
这些 view 中的每一个，年视图，月视图，日视图，
view, and the appointment view are their own MVCs.
任务视图，都有他们自己的 MVC
Okay?
But you can see how the last three, okay,
但是你可以发现，最后三个 view,
are used as essentially a minion of the top level view,
都被最顶层的年视图为了展示更多的细节
year view, to show more detail, okay?
而被当做仆从使用
So the year view,you click on a month,
所以在年视图里，你点击了一个月份，
it's going to use the month view MVC to show more detail.
它会利用月份视图的 MVC 来展现更多细节
So it's part of its view,okay?
所以它是它视图的一部分，
So, you see this also in iOS with tab bar
所以你也在带有 tab bar 的 iOS 应用
controllers, right?
中见过这些吧
You have the tab bar at the bottom, I have four or
在底部有一个 tab bar，有四个或五个
five things you can choose.
项可以供你选择
Well there's some MVC at the top whose has four pointers to
在上面有一个 MVC，它指向四个仆从，
four minions, which are the four MVCs that are each going
也就是将要出现在
to appear in a tab bar, okay?
tab bar 的 MVC，
We'll be doing that for
我们将会做一个这方面的 demo，
example, in assignment number two or
在第二次或第三次作业，我们会
three where we'll be making a tab bar and
制作一个 tab bar，
you're gonna have to do multiple MVCs, okay?
你们将会学习如何使用多个 MVC
So, that basically results in a picture looks kinda
所以使用多个 MVC 的效果看起来就像
like this.
这张图片一样
All right?
Where you got this MVC, and
在你看到的这个 MVC 里，
you see the purple one that's like underneath the word
找到'together' 下面的那个
together there, and
紫色的，
it points to three other MVCs outside of its view thing.
它从 view 指向了另外三个 MVC，
Okay?
That's how we're going to build it, so
这就是我们创建 tab bar 的方式，
that might be a tab bar control and
这些可能就是它的
those might be the three tabs.
三个标签
Okay, and each one is its own little MVC
并且它们每一个都是
completely independent, operates on its own.
完全独立的，可以独自行动的小 MVC
Doesn't even know,
这时它就是一个
it's a generic reusable view like thing at this point.
普通的可重用的 view 之类的东西，
Doesn't even know that it's in a tab bar.
它甚至不知道它在 tab bar 中
Okay, it just knows that it's supposed to do
它只知道它应该做
whatever it does.
这些事情
And so it's modular in that way.
所以在这方面，它是模块化的
You can also see that there's no communication between any
可以看到这里不再有其他箭头，
other, there's no other arrows, except for
除了
some of the models.
一些 model
You see some of the models are communicating with each other.
某些 model 之间在互相通信
You know a big
要知道，
application might have a single shared model.
一个大型的应用也许会有一个单独的共享 model
Or the models might be split off into pieces to be used by
或者，model 会被分开来
sub MVCs.
供子 MVC 使用
Okay? But
但是，
that's the only kind of communication you have there.
这里只能使用这种通信方式
All other communication is
其它所有的通信
either the structure view communication we saw on MVC,
要么是 MVC 中的结构化通信，
or it's using MVCs as part of the view of another MVC.
要么是将 MVC 用作另一个 MVC 视图的一部分
Any question about that?
有问题吗？
So we definitely don't want to be having designs that
所以我们当然不希望
look like this, okay?
设计成这样，
Where everybody's talking to everybody.
所有都在互相通信，
We can't tell who's talking to what.
我们不能分清谁在和什么通信
It's just impossible to debug a program like this, and
这会让调试程序变得异常艰难，
it doesn't scale.
而且它无法规模化
You can't build really big programs this way.
你不能通过这种方式创建出大程序
It just becomes impossible to
这样的话，
know how touching anything would break everything, right?
你无法弄清楚，什么地方会引发整个程序的崩溃
So we're definitely not going to be doing that.
所以我们绝对不会这样做的
All right so that's MVC and,
所以，这就是 MVC，
like I say, on Monday we'll apply MVC to our calculator.
我们将会在周一的课里把 MVC 应用到我们的 calculator 中
So what's coming up?
所以，接下来是什么？
I always try to get to this slide every lecture.
我每节课都尽量讲到这里，
Sometimes I forget but it's posted in the slides.
有时我会忘记，但是它被放到了课件中
It says tomorrow is Friday.
周五也就是明天，
No, day after tomorrow is Friday.
不对，后天的周五，
And people who are watching on iTunes U,
在 iTunes U 上观看的同学们，
these Friday sections will not be on iTunes U so
周五的部分不会被放到 iTunes U 上，
don't go looking for them only the normal Monday,
只有周一和周三的才会被放上去，
Wednesday lectures went on iTunes U.
所以不要到处找
But, for Stanford students,
但是对于在坐的同学，
Friday we have this debugger section we talked about.
周五我们将讨论之前谈到的调试部分
And then next Monday,
下周一，你们的阅读作业
your reading assignment is gonna be due.
将会截至
In other words, you should be done with that
换句话说，你应当在周一上课之前
reading assignment before the start of Monday's lecture.
完成阅读作业
And I'm gonna assign you another reading assignment.
我会再布置给你们一个阅读作业
It might be your only other reading assignment.
它将会是你们最后一个阅读作业
Perhaps there'll be a reassignment three,
也许以后还会有阅读作业，
but it won't be any more than that.
但是不会像那个一样多
And then on Wednesday I'm
下周三，我会深入介绍
really gonna dive into Swift and Foundation.
Swift 语言和 Foundation 框架
I'm gonna talk a little bit about the Objective C legacy,
我将会介绍一点遗留下来的 Objective-C
and then your assignment one is gonna be
你们的作业一将会在
due a week from today.
一周后截止
It's been posted for you, and your assignment two is gonna
你们已经看到了，作业二将会在
go out next Wednesday and be due the Wednesday after that.
下周三布置下去，下下周三截止
Just for a little bit of advanced planning for
提前为你们所有人
all of you.
做一些计划
Okay?
Any other questions?
还有问题吗？
Okay, thank you.
好的，谢谢
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
>> 想了解更多，请登录 stanford.edu